片名：东京上空三十秒
你好，请稍等。您的电话，上校
Yes? Just a minute. Your call, Colonel.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好，约克上校吗？请讲
Hello. Captain York, please.
你知道，这件事如果计划周密
You know, if this thing works out,
将会给我们驻守在从巴丹半岛到新加坡的小伙子们极大的鼓舞
it might give our boys all the way from Bataan to Singapore a big lift.
并把那些日本人赶回他们的小岛上去
And it may pull a lot of Japs back to their islands.
- 一定会的，将军
- It'll work out, General.
- 我也相信
- I'm sure it will
喂，约克，我是杜利德
Hello. Hello, York? Doolittle.
约克，我要你准备好24架B-25轰炸机和志愿飞行员
York, I want you to get 24 B-25s with volunteer crews
尽快调遣到埃格林空军基地
down to Eglin Field as soon as you can.
这项任务会让他们远离国土三个月
The job will take them out of the country for about three months.
告诉他们这是一项秘密任务
Tell them it's a secret mission.
到达那里之前他们是不会知道目的地的
They won't know where they're going until they get there.
对，志愿飞行员
That's right, volunteers.
告诉他们不准向任何人谈起, 这是命令
Tell them they're not to talk to anybody. That's an order.
我过几天就会来。好的
I'll join you in a few days. Right.
02241呼叫埃格林指挥塔
Zero-two-two-four-one to Eglin Tower.
3架B-25请求飞行和降落指示
Three B-25s request traffic and landing instructions.
请讲
Go ahead.
41军，请靠左飞行
Army four-one. The left-hand pattern.
风向，北偏东北
Wind direction north by northeast.
在3号跑道降落
Land on runway number three.
那是个机场吧？
There's the field all right.
嘿，你们见过这么宽的跑道吗？
Boy, did you ever see such a wide runway?
它的确很大啊
She's big all right.
你完全可以闭着眼睛着陆
You could almost close your eyes and get in.
我真想知道，我们会从这儿飞往哪里
And I'd give plenty to know where we go from here.
我也想知道
Yeah, so would I.
嘿，先别降落，我去拿相机
Hey, don't do anything till I get my camera.
机鼻的景色怎么样，克勒文？
How does she look from the nose, Clever?
太棒了，佛罗里达、棕榈树、美洲鳄、泳装美人
Great. Florida, palm trees, alligators, bathing beauties.
嘿，撒切尔，看一下脚下的景色怎么样
Hey, Thatcher, have a look at some real country.
没有比令斯漂亮，长官
It's not as pretty as Billings, sir.
这次飞行带饼干了吗，撒切尔？
Did you keep the cookies this trip, Thatcher?
是的，长官，带了，飞跃山脉时我很难受，但我还是挺过来了
Yes, sir. I had a little trouble coming over the mountains, but I hung on.
- 02241
- Zero-two-two-four-one to flight.
- 嘿，等会儿
- Hey, wait a minute.
我们先等会儿，把飞行梯队编好
We'll go around, make an echelon right
先飞到机场上空，然后再解散梯队做得漂亮点
once over the field, then break away. Let's make it pretty.
但愿好运
Here's for luck.
关闭
Switch is off!
- 5分25秒，还不赖
- 5:25. Not bad time
- 我们走了
- Yeah, we moved.
最好去报修一下左边的引擎，它的声音有点刺耳
Better write that left engine up. She sounded a little rough.
我干得不错吧，劳森？
Boy, I got some swell shots, Lawson.
你的降落真完美，给我一种艺术的视觉享受
You really made a nice break away. Gave me kind of an artistic angle.
总有一天我要干一次坠毁降落，这样你就能看上真正的电影了
Some day I'll do a crash landing so you can get a real movie.
撒切尔说佛罗里达比不上比令斯
Thatcher says that Florida can't compare to Billings.
撒切尔是觉得，任何超过300人的地方…
Trouble with Thatcher is he thinks that any place with more than 300 people
- 便很拥挤了
- is overcrowded.
- 是根据最近一次人口普查的，长官
- Oh, according to the last census, sir,
比令斯有16,300人口
Billings has a population of 16,380.
16,000，不会吧，撒切尔，你一定把郊区算进去了
16,000! Oh, no, Thatcher, you must be thinking of Greater Billings.
不，他说对了，克勒文，他们把乡间的奶牛算进去了
No, he's right, Clever. They count the cows up in that country.
- 对不起，长官
- Sorry, sir.
- 什么事？
- Yes.
- 机场禁止照相
- Cameras aren't allowed on the field.
- 什么？
- What?
是的，长官
That's right, sir.
许多秘密工事都在这里，这是很严肃的纪律
A lot of secret work goes on here, and they're very strict about it.
我根本没看见有什么秘密工事
Well, I can't see anything secret from here.
那么我只好向指挥官报告了，长官
Then I'll have to report youto the Commanding Officer, sir.
这是我的职责
Those are my orders.
好吧。好吧
Okay. Okay.
瞧，布里.霍尔斯通还和我们在一起
Hey, look, Brick Holstrom's still with us.
我还在想明天之前，你不会把那个笨蛋叫上的
We were afraid you wouldn't get that turkey in till tomorrow.
为什么？那家伙飞得挺好的
Why, that baby flies so pretty
最后200英里我们很平稳
we floated the last 200 miles.
- 你们准备好了吗？
- Are you guys ready?
- 好了，来吧，布里克
- Yeah. Come on, Brick.
撒切尔，我去去就来，还要告诉你的住处
Oh, Thatcher, I'll be right back and tell you where your quarters are.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
戴维，有什么想法？说说看
Come on, Davey, you've got an idea. What's the dope?
- 我们从这儿会到哪儿去？
- Where do we go from here?
- 我告诉过你了
- I already told you.
他们只说了我们会离开本土
All they said was that it'd take us out of the country,
我们会离开3个月，而且还有一定的危险
we'd be gone about three months and that it'd be dangerous.
听着，我从乔兰德尔那里，得到了真实内幕
Look, I got the real dope from Joe Randall.
他说我们是要组成巡逻中队，去保卫巴拿马运河
He says they're forming patrol squadrons to guard the Canal.
运河巡逻有什么危险？
What's dangerous about Canal patrol?
那么，我们担心什么呢？
Well, what are we worrying about?
当我们报到时，斯基就会告诉我们内幕了
Ski will give us all the dope when we check in anyhow.
三架飞机到，长官，霍尔斯通、劳森和我
Three ships in, sir. Holstrom, Lawson, and myself.
- 好的，你们的飞机还好吧？
- Good. Your ships okay?
- 是的，长官
- Yes, sir.
坐吧
Sit down.
我们住哪，斯基？
Where we staying, Ski?
政府在附近租了间旅馆
The government's leased a hotel near here.
他们叫军官俱乐部
They call it the Officers' Club.
带来的家眷也可以待在那里
The men whose wives are coming can stay there.
其他军官的住处在5号兵营
The other officers' quarters are in Barracks 5.
艾米来了吗？
Is Emmy coming down?
- 她几天之后到
- She'll be here in a couple of days.
- 斯基，撒切尔住哪？
- Where'll I put Thatcher, Ski?
招募兵被安排在12号兵营
The enlisted men are assigned to Barracks 12.
好的
Okay.
- 还有其他事吗？
- Anything else?
- 没了
- Nope?
至少明早之前没事了
At least, not until tomorrow morning.
那好，我们再会
Well, we'll be seeing you.
喂，斯基，大伙儿都很想知道发生什么了
Say, Ski, the guys are all crazy to know what's up.
你和我知道的差不多
You know as much about it as I do.
明早我们就会得到更多消息了
We may be given more information in the morning.
快瞧，伙计，谁来了
Well, beat me, daddy! Look who's coming!
好！好！好！看来我必须去了
Well, well, well, plant me now and dig me later,
如果不是伦道夫.菲尔德的缘故。怎么样，哥们？
if it isn't the pride of Randolph Field. How are you, boy?
最近不错，我们一听到这个兴奋的消息
Great, Shorty. The minute we heard that razzmatazz,
就知道你肯定就在这附近
we knew you must be somewhere around.
- 你也是自愿参与这次行动的
- You volunteer for this deal, too?
- 那是当然
- Sure enough.
他们把我安排在明尼阿波利斯,一个我见过最冷的地方
They had me stationed up in Minneapolis. Coldest country I ever did see.
我极力想去任何一个，能让我重返阳光的地方
I'd have volunteered for anything to get back in the sunshine.
- 你去过哪？
- Where you been?
- 哥伦比亚、南卡罗莱纳
- Columbia, South Carolina.
- 鲍勃
- Bob!
- 你好，特德
- Hello, Ted.
你们互相认识？
You guys know each other?
我们一起认识的凯利，就这样
Oh, we just went through Kelly together, that's all.
- 当然，鲍勃是我婚礼的伴郎
- Sure. Bob was bridesmaid at my wedding.
- 婚礼
- Wedding?
没有人再告诉我什么了
Nobody tells me anything anymore.
你们搞在一起多久了？
How long you been balled up and chained down?
再过五六天就六个月了
Six months, in five more days.
让我大吃一惊啊，别骗我啊
Well, blow my foot off. Skin me again, boy.
戴维，你在这儿怎么样啊？
Hey, Davey, what are you doing down here?
- 布里克
- Brick!
- 嗨，唐
- Hi, Don.
- 我还以为你在打潜水艇呢
- I thought you were hunting subs.
- 是啊，打沉过一艘
- Was. Got me one, too.
- 你也参与这项任务
- You in on this deal?
- 当然，我有一批不错的队员
- Sure. I've got a swell crew
看起来好像会有什么大任务，不是吗？
and it looked like it was going to be something, so why not?
- 我们的行动，有什么想法吗？
- Any ideas what we might be up to?
- 哦，只是预感
- Oh, just a hunch.
是吗？快说说看
Yeah? Well, give.
南部海域赶走那些蠢蛋
South Seas. Knock ourselves off a few meatballs.
三点
Three.
好家伙，庄家得两点
Honest man. Dealer takes two.
- 我刚才想到
- You know, I just got an idea.
- 想到什么？
- About what?
想到我们会去的地方
About where we might be going.
- 行程看起来会…
- The way it looks to...
- 不会不会，算了
- No, that's not right. Forget it.
得两点
Says two.
- 我也有一个猜想
- You know, I've got an idea too.
- 什么？
- Yeah?
我觉得，你肯定是第一个来到这里…
I've got an idea you're pretty much of a dope
并且是知道内情的人
to have come in on this deal in the first place.
为什么这样认为？
What kind of a crack is that?
我不知道你结婚了，有一个不错的女孩
Oh, I don't know. You're married. You've got a swell girl.
如果我是你的话，就绝不会去冒风险
I never would have stuck my neck out if I were in your boots.
滚开，你说两点
Go away. You say two?
再跟两点
And up two.
那些人又被刷掉了
Those guys are off again.
起来，起来。你们以为你们是谁啊
Hey, stand up there. Who do you think you are?
你们飞机上配有导航员吗？
Have you ever carried a navigator in your ship before, Spike?
我也没有，直到我们参与了这次行动
Neither have I, until I volunteered for this job.
我们就快知道一些奇妙的消息了，我有一种感党
Oh, we're going to see some fancy stuff, all right. I kind of got a feeling.
拿我们去对付那些臭鸡貂
Shoot me for a pole cat.
我看见两个精力充沛的人，背靠背…
Do I see two red-blooded citizens lying on their backsides
还唱着得克萨斯赞歌
while the Texas anthem is being rendered?
起立，所有人
On your feet, men.
感觉怎么样？最近你来自佛吉尼亚吧？
What are you beefing about, Shorty? You're from Virginia.
是的，聪明鬼
That's right, sharp cat,
但我德州的这个朋友在这，而且经常不守规矩
but my pal here, he's from Texas, and he takes offense easy.
- 你好，乔
- Hello, Joe.
- 你好，乔伊斯，我得到一些消息
- Hello, Joyce. I've got some news.
嘿，你们几个，安静些
Hey, you guys, shut up!
安静，小伙子们。听着，吉米.杜利德要来了
Quiet, fellows. Listen. Jimmy Doolittle's down here
他现在是陆军中校
and he's a Lieutenant Colonel now.
吉米.杜利德是南加州的
Jimmy Doolittle! A southern boy from Southern California.
让我们为吉米.杜利德唱一曲“德州之眼”吧
Let's have Eyes of Texas for Lieutenant Colonel Jimmy Doolittle.
立正
Attention!
先生，杜利德中校
Gentlemen, Lieutenant Colonel Doolittle.
请坐
As you were.
你们是自愿到这儿的
You men are here because you've volunteered.
你们被告知，这将会是一次危险的任务
You have been told it's a dangerous mission.
现在我不会再告诉你们更多，但我想再强调危险
I can't tell you any more than that now, but I want to emphasize the danger.
当下最重要的是严守秘密
The most important thing at the moment is secrecy.
我不想你们去告诉你们的妻子，这里有些什么
I don't want you to even tell your wives what you see down here.
如果你们觉得猜到了，将要去哪儿…
And if you think you've guessed where you're going,
你那肯定是错的，但甚至这猜测都不要谈论
you're probably wrong. But don't even talk about your guess.
如果这次任务的一丁点消息走漏了的话…
If the slightest word about this mission gets around,
你们的生命甚至数以万计人的生命，都将置于危险之中
you will endanger not only your own lives, but the lives of thousands of other men.
现在，我想问你们一个问题
Now I want to ask you a question.
有人试着谈起这些事情吗？
Has anybody tried to talk to you about this?
很好，如果基地内外的任何人…
Good. If anybody on the field or off the field
试看要问起你们关于…
tries to engage you in conversation
为什么你们来这里，不管多么友善…
as to why you're here, no matter how innocently,
我要你们记住他的名字，然后告诉我
I want you to get his name and give it to me
我会把它交给联邦调查局
and I'll turn it over to the FBI.
这将是一次你们经历过的最艰苦的训练
This is going to be the toughest training you've ever had.
你们将会在同一艘船上和同一批人在一起
You will have the same crew all the way through and the same ship.
任何失败的机组将会被剔除
And the man or the ship that fails will be dropped.
你们将会驾驶你们觉得不可能的用B-25飞行的方法
You're going to do things with a B-25 you thought were impossible.
现在，如果你们有任何杂念，我建议你们趁早放弃
Now, if any of you have any doubts, I'd like you to drop out right now
我保证你们没有人会想得更糟
and I promise you that no one will ever think the worse of you.
如果你们的妻儿或其他什么…
If you have wives or children or any other considerations
让你们在危机中时刻牵挂着，很正常
that might get on your nerves in a crisis, it's perfectly all right.
事实上，放弃是你们的职责
As a matter of fact, it's your duty to drop out.
很好，我们将进行尽可能多的谈话，就这样吧
Very well. We'll have these talks as often as possible. That's all.
今早开始，我们将进行定向飞行
We're going up this morning for an orientation flight.
有四个辅助机场，一、二、三、四
There are four auxiliary fields. One, two, three, four.
依次全部找到它们
Line them up and locate them all.
我不知道会使用哪一个来进行，我们的机密试验…
We don't know which we're going to use for our confidential experiments,
所以自己都去熟悉熟悉
so familiarize yourselves with all of them.
先自己去转转。等一会儿我们再集台
Look over the countryside, and we'll meet here again
下午三点半，还有问题吗？
at 3:30 this afternoon. Are there any questions?
长官，我引擎中的塞子正在更换中
Sir, the plugs are being changed in my engines.
为了节省时间，我能搭琼斯的飞机吗？
To save time, may I go along in Jones' ship?
可以，史密斯。你们可以去自己的飞机了
Right, Smith. All right. You can go to your ship now.
对我来说，你很长时间都没去…
It looks to me like it's going to be a long time
比令斯主干道游荡了，撒切尔
before you swing down Main Street of Billings again, Thatcher.
在比令斯，长官，主干道是明尼苏达大街
In Billings, sir, the main street is Minnesota Avenue.
你知道，那个人很当真的
You know, that guy really means business.
- 他让我有点出汗
- He had me sweating a little.
- 我也是
- Yeah, me too.
- 劳森中尉？
- Lieutenant Lawson?
- 是的
- Yes.
有人看见你在J大街的陆军消费合作社前，长官
Someone to see you out in front of the PX at J Street, sir.
谢谢，我想会是谁…
Thanks. I wonder who would...
我马上就来
I'll be right back.
爱伦
Ellen!
- 你从哪儿来？
- Where did you come from?
- 我开到卡罗莱纳来给你个惊喜
- I drove to Carolina to surprise you.
- 他们告诉我你在这里
- And then they told me you're down here.
- 是吗？还好吧
- Well, how are you?
凑合，谢谢，你怎么样？
I'm just fine, thank you. And how are you bearing up?
还好，你一点都没变
Oh, great. You look just the same.
当然没变，你不能总是期望立刻就变
Well, of course I do. You can't expect any change this soon.
- 什么意思？
- What's the joke?
- 没什么
- Nothing.
没想到你这么搞笑
Except you're so funny.
告诉我亲爱的，你惊讶吗？
Tell me, honey, were you surprised?
我简直不敢相信我的眼睛，等会儿，我去给你买点喝的
Oh, I couldn't believe my eyes. Here, let me buy you a drink.
真高兴见到你
Gee, I'm glad to see you.
来，我们到处走走
Come on, let's go around here.
告诉我甜心，为什么你这么可人？
Tell me, honey, how come you're so cute?
我找到了一个如此帅气的小伙子，我必须得这样啊
I had to be if I were going to get such a good looking fellow.
我有千言万语想对你说
You know, there's a lot of things I want to talk over with you.
说吧，你真的很惊讶吗？
Go ahead. Were you really surprised?
其实不是非常
Well, no, not exactly.
你知道吗？当你睁开双眼时就会变成这样
You know, you go into something like this with your eyes open.
- 自然你得抓住机会
- Naturally you've got to take your chances.
- I see.
- 我知道
这样看着它不是有些冷漠吗？
Isn't that kind of a cold-blooded way to look at it?
快别发疯了，你真的有点冷漠了
Oh, now, don't get mad. You've got to be cold-blooded about it.
这对我来说是最重要的事
This is the most important thing that's ever happened to me.
- 那我呢？
- What about me?
- 你也是啊
- Well, you're in on it, too.
- 这就是我为什么想说一说的原因
- That's why I want to talk it over.
- 真慷慨啊，说吧，特德
- That's very generous. Go on, Ted.
那么，首先我们得保守秘密
Well, in the first place, we've got to keep it a secret.
- 我也不是要你从心底发誓
- I don't want you to tell a soul.
- 你是，我是说，你…
- You're not, I mean, you...
你不希望这一切发生，是吗？
You don't wish it hadn't happened, do you?
哦，是的，当然
Oh, no, of course not.
但这是军事机密，我有我的纪律
But it's a military secret, I've got my orders.
军事…比如，你说的…
Military... Say, what are you talking about?
比如我自愿参与的这项任务，你收到我的信了吗？
Well, this job I volunteered for. Didn't you get my letter?
- 没有，你收到我的了吗？
- No. Didn't you get mine?
- 没有
- No.
我觉得这很可笑，但是…
Well, I suppose it's very funny, but...
- 嗨，劳森，特德.劳森
- Hey, Lawson! Ted Lawson!
- 到
- Here.
你们藏起来干什么？
What are you hiding out...
- 爱伦，什么时候来的？
- Ellen, when did you get here?
- 5分钟前，我的伴娘还好吧？
- Five minutes ago. How's my bridesmaid?
很好，只是我不得不打断你们了
Great. Only I'm going to have to break this up.
杜利德来视察我们起飞了
Doolittle came out to watch us take off.
好，晚饭时我来找你
Okay. I'll see you for dinner.
顺着路下去一英里半有家旅馆
There's a hotel about a mile and a half down the road.
我还没去过呢，但他们说你一定能找到的
I haven't seen it yet, but they tell me you can't miss it.
- 我会找到的
- I'll find it.
- 很抱歉这样行事匆忙
- I'm sorry to have to rush off like this.
别忘了晚餐
Don't forget dinner.
有人捡到我的信了吗？
Say, did anybody pick up a letter for me?
是的，长官，我今早捡到的，我都快忘了
Yes, sir. I did this morning. I forgot all about it.
- 好的，把它拿来
- Well, bring it up.
- 是的
- Yes, sir.
对不起，长官
I'm sorry, sir.
好的，谢谢，你来开好吗，达文波特？
Okay. Thanks. Take over, will you, Davenport.
好的
Sure.
哇，我有孩子了
Hey! I'm going to have a baby!
是爱伦写的
Hey, it's from Ellen.
她就要是…我是说，我就要当爸爸了
She's going to be... I mean, I'm going to be a father.
你好，飞行员
Hello, flyer.
对不起叫醒你们
Oh, I'm sorry I woke you up.
我没睡着，真的，我在假寐冥思
I wasn't sleeping, really. I was just dozing and thinking.
我没能赶回来吃晚餐，真对不起，我们有太多的检验工作
I'm sorry I didn't get back for dinner. We had a lot of checking to do.
你肯定觉得，我今早就是个大笨蛋
You must've thought I was an awful dope this morning.
我直到后来才收到你的信，所以那时我根本不知道
But I didn't get your letter until later, so I didn't know.
我知道，坐吧
I know. Sit down.
- 我认为孩子的事太美妙了
- I think it's swell about the baby.
- 我知道你会这样的，我一点也不担心
- I knew you would. I wasn't a bit worried.
你知道 ，这真好玩
You know, it's going to seem funny.
我不在乎男孩女孩，一点都不重要
I don't care whether it's a boy or a girl. Not that much.
我只要你一切都好，我是认真的
I just want you to be okay. It's pretty serious.
- 什么这么好笑
- Well, what's so funny?
- 我刚才在想
- I was just thinking.
这里你在准备完成些，非常困难的任务…
Here you're getting ready to go off on something really tough,
那里还在牵挂着我
and you're worrying about me.
如果我是你，肯定都吓死了
If I were in your spot, I'd be scared to death.
- 我觉得我就是这样的
- But I guess I am anyhow.
- 纯粹的例行公事，飞行员
- Purely routine stuff, flyer.
这是每个女孩子生中都要经的一两次
The kind of job every girl takes on once or twice in her life.
你为何不躺下？
Why don't you lie down?
你知道吗，爱伦？
You know, Ellen,
拥有你我已经心满意足
I'm kind of glad I got you.
我想这就是我刚才睡觉时想的
I guess that's what I was thinking about in my sleep.
快把我吓住了
It almost frightened me.
就好像我在想，如果我们没有相遇会怎样
It seemed that I was thinking, "What if I'd never met him?"
有一点是…
Well, for one thing
你不会遍行全国…
you wouldn't be traipsing around the country
从一个空军基地到另一个努力地找我
from one airfield to another trying to catch up with me.
还有就是…
And for another,
你不会在战争之际怀上了一个孩子
you wouldn't be having a baby right in the middle of a war.
不是，不是那样
3Oh, no, it wasn't that.
我在想如果我没有遇见你…
I was thinking that if I hadn't met you,
我的生命中便没有人能像你一样和我如此亲近
I'd never have felt really close to anybody, never in my whole life.
结婚六月，相聚不到两周
Married six months and together less than two weeks.
这不是我说的亲近
That's not being as close as I'd figured on.
特德，你不觉得就是这样吗？
Don't you see, Ted, that's just it.
两人远在天边，却心有所属…
If people can be close when they're far away from each other,
那才是应该有的
well, that's what it should be.
是是，我也这么想
Yeah, yeah, I guess so.
抱紧我
Cuddle me.
我想起了上个圣诞节
I was thinking about last Christmas.
在波特兰汽车旅馆立的那棵圣诞树
The tree we set up in that Portland auto court.
- 那间屋子不是很小吗？
- Wasn't it an awful little room?
- 是啊
- Yeah.
我们在准备圣诞晚餐
And the Christmas dinner we were planning on.
然后你把煤气用光了
And then you ran out of gas and landed in the mud up in lllwaco,
我再见你已是圣诞节之后了
Christmas Eve and Christmas were all over before I saw you again.
对，真的很难熬，但无论如何我都挺过来了
Yeah, that was tough. But I got a scarf out of it, anyhow.
这并不和我们的计划一致
Well, it wasn't exactly as we'd planned it.
这是我们的第一个圣诞节,在一个遥远地地方
It was our first Christmas, and somewhere way off,
什么地方不重要
it didn't matter where,
只要我有了你，特德,这是我一生中最美好的一个圣涎
I knew I had you. Oh, Ted, it was the nicest Christmas of my life.
爱伦，你今生注定会嫁给一个飞行员的从我看见你的第一眼起就这样想了
You were born to marry a flyer, Ellen. I knew that the minute I first saw you.
事实上，这就是我嫁给你的理由
As a matter of fact that's why I married you.
- 我想对你说句告白
- You know, I've got a confession to make.
- 什么？
- What?
事实是，不是你娶了我,是我嫁给了你
The truth is, you didn't marry me. I married you.
是吗？
Oh, you did, eh?
我在洛杉矾城市学院国书馆第一次看见你…
The first time I saw you in the library at LACC,
我就对自己说：噢，他会是我的
I said to myself, "Oh, oh, that's for me. "
从那时起
And from then on,
从那一个个美好的夜晚,到离开那个爱荷达的小镇
clear up to the night we got the judge out of bed in that little Idaho town,
没有什么是偶然，特德
nothing was an accident, Ted.
都是我设计的
I planned it that way.
- 你觉得你很聪慧，是吗？
- You think you're pretty smart, don't you?
- 我自己也不确定
- I'm not sure whether I do or not.
你瞧，你并没有表现出十足的战斗力
You see, you didn't put up much of a fight.
我想你也在考虑孩子
I suppose you figured out on that baby, too?
那是你根本不可能知道的,飞行员根本不知道
That's something you'll never know, flyer, you'll never know.
这几天小伙子们都熬得很晚啊
Boys are working late these nights.
是啊，你认为你们会离开多久？
Yes. Do you have any idea how long you'll be gone?
但只要任务结束,我就会去要求一个假期
But as soon as this job is over, I'm going to ask for a leave.
也许两到三周
Two, maybe three weeks.
我们可以度蜜月了,以前你不是总提起吗？
We'll have that honeymoon you're always talking about.
是的，就我们仨
Yes, just the three of us.
特德
Ted.
我真希望我不要长得又肥又丑,就像芝加哥肥婆一样
I do hope I don't get big and fat like that lady in Chicago.
我想要你们每个人都知道一些其他人的工作
I want each one of you to know something about the other man's job.
飞行员会担负飞机上的一切任务
The pilots will practice every job on the plane.
导航员要学学投弹手的工作
等等
以防你们当中有人被击中
Navigators will learn the work of bombardiers and so forth.
还有一件事
That's in case any of you get shot up.
不可避免的事,你们当中的某些飞机…
It is inevitable that some of your planes
会落入敌人手中
are going to fall into the hands of the enemy.
出于这样的考虑，我命令你们拆掉诺登投弹瞄准器
For this reason, I have ordered your Norden bombsights removed.
格里宁上校研发了一种简易瞄准器, 很适合你们的
Captain Greening has designed a sight which will be perfect for our job.
如果没什么问题了，那么就请约克上校来说说
If there are no questions, I'll ask Captain York to take over.
刚才我说过，我们去巴西巡逻
Just like I said, we patrol off Brazil.
那么为什么我们要拆掉诺登投弹瞄准器？
Yeah, but what about taking the Norden Bombsight out?
如果我们是去打击潜艇的话，根本不可能被敌机击中
There's no chance of falling into the hands of the enemy if you're hunting subs.
- 我从不那样认为
- I hadn't thought of that.
- 那都是杜利德的鬼话，是吧？
- That Doolittle's a cheerful cuss, isn't he?
以防你们当中有人被击中被灿烂的阳光击中
"Just in case any of us are shot up," a bundle of sunshine.
哦，那是特德，特德
Oh, it's Ted, it's Ted!
我们第一次结婚时乔治也这样嗡嗡从我身边开过
George used to buzz me when we were first married.
他再也不那样了，这是不允许的
He doesn't do it any more. They're not supposed to.
- 我怀疑他是否还爱我
- I wonder if he still loves me.
- 我可一点也不担心
- I wouldn't worry about that.
每次斯基有了一架新飞机就像爱上了它似的
Every time Ski gets a new ship he has a terrible love affair with it,
但他总会回到我身边的
but he always comes back to me,
尤其是当他饿得咕咕叫时
especially when he's hungry.
想想看他们会离开三个月
Just think, they'll be gone three months.
我想我会在国防工厂找到一份工作
I think I'll get a job in a defense factory.
我真的不能忍受坐在一间小公寓，无尽等待，无所事事
I couldn't stand just sitting around in some little apartment and waiting.
你打算怎么办，爱伦？
What are you going to do, Ellen?
我想静下心来，因为我有孩子了
Oh, I'm just going to sit around and have a baby.
- 一个孩子
- A baby!
爱伦，为什么不告诉我们？
Ellen, why didn't you tell us?
我不知道，或许我一直没想好怎么说直到刚才
I don't know. I guess I just never thought of a way till now.
既然这样了，说说也不难啊
As it turns out, it wasn't hard to tell at all.
好吧，我也有了一个孩子了
Well, I'm going to have one, too.
- 是么
- What?
- 真的吗？
- Really?
珍，我觉得这样太棒了
Gee, I think it's wonderful.
乔治和我商量过的，但现在他走了…
George and I have talked about it, but, well, with him away and all,
- 我想我可能太害怕了
I guess I'm just too scared.
- 我也害怕，但是…
- I thought I would be too, but...
特德和我猜想珍珠港事件后的每一件事…
Well, Ted and I figured that everything since Pearl Harbor
都如此顺利
has just been so much velvet.
我想如果他发生了什么事…
And then I guessed that if anything should happen to him,
我知道不会发生的
only I know nothing will,
我就会把小孩生下来，这就是特德仍然活着的希望
I'd have the baby, and that would be a little bit of Ted still living.
我有时想知道，等一切都结束了，我们会怎样
I sometimes wonder how we'll feel when it's all over.
试想，在某个地方安顿下来找一件小房子…
Just think, being able to settle down in a little house somewhere
抚养你们的小孩，无忧无虑
and raise your children and never be in doubt about anything.
我对现在的生活…
We'll probably have exactly the same doubts
倒想打一个问号.
that we have right now.
比如，他会回来吃晚饭吗？
For example, will he or will he not be home for dinner?
我们将要进行本次训练中最机密的一部分
We're about to enter the most secret part of our training.
机场周边都部署了巡逻，所以没人能打扰你们
This field is patrolled on all sides so no one can disturb you at your work.
先生们，这是米勒海军上尉
Gentlemen, this is Lieutenant Miller of the Navy.
他将指示你们的起飞
He's going to instruct you in takeoffs.
除了正常的B-25在1500英尺内以90英里的时速起飞…
Instead of the normal B-25 takeoff in 1,500 feet at 90 miles an hour,
他还会教你们…
he's going to show you how to do it
全负荷炸弹和汽油时，在500英尺内以50英里的时速起飞
with a full load of bombs and gas in 500 feet at 50 miles an hour.
你们将尝试短距离起飞
You will attempt no short takeoffs
从埃格林空军基地，大家都可以看到
from Eglin Field, where people can see you.
米勒海军上尉还会给你们一些海军礼仪讲座
Lieutenant Miller will also give you a few short talks on naval etiquette.
如果我说的这些让你们现在觉察到了有关你们的目的地…
Now, if this gives you any hints as to your destination
和此次任务的蛛丝马迹…
or as to what kind of work you're going to do,
不要在下面议论
don't even discuss it among yourselves.
接下来的时间我要交给米勒海军上尉
I'll ask Lieutenant Miller to take over now.
先生们
Gentlemen,
这些旗子距离起点有…
those flags out there are at
100、200、300、400和500英尺远
100, 200, 300, 400, and 500 feet from the starting line.
训练场中间的这些线是引导你们起飞的
The line down the center of the field is to guide you in your takeoff.
你们的任务不允许有任何的背离
The kind of work you're going to do won't permit any deviations.
现在记住，在你松开刹车之前，要把动力推到最大
Now, the whole idea is to get up full power before you release your brakes.
然后开始以最大转率加压
Then start, at maximum r. p. m., manifold pressure
让机翼侧翼立起来
and with your wing flaps all the way down.
你们要加快发动机转率，直到你认为它快要燃烧起来为止
You'll have to rev your motors until you think they're going to burn up.
然后如果它们向右倾斜
And then, when they reach the right pitch,
声音和感觉比指令更重要
and that's a matter of sound and feel more than instruments,
放开刹车去见上帝吧
release your brakes and hunt for heaven.
我不想你们第一次都去尝试这样
I don't expect any of you to do it the first time.
- 格雷
- Gray.
- 是，长官
- Yes, sir.
你和门奇是不是想第一个试试
Suppose you and Manch try it first?
剩下的人待在地面评判你们的表现，观测一下风速
The rest of us will stay on the ground, mark your takeoff and check the wind.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
我觉得最开始我们可以从观看、试飞中学到…
I think at first we can learn as much by watching trial runs
和实际飞行一样多的东西
as by actually flying the ships.
那么我们就在这里排好队，看看他们怎么表现
So let's all line up over here and see how he does.
- 地表风速怎样，斯基？
- What kind of surface wind, Ski?
- 每小时8英里
- Eight miles an hour.
他没有把引擎转速提升到足够快
He didn't have his engines revved up enough.
劳森，你接着去
Lawson, you go next.
记住，我们的目的是
Now remember, for our purposes,
如果你把你的一个轮子飞离地面，就足够好了
if you get your wheels a foot off the ground, that's good enough.
不需要太高，但一定要让轮子离开地面
You don't need height, but you've got to get your wheels off
但不要碰到旗子
before you hit the last flag.
等一会儿我们会尝试，在450英尺内收回轮子
A little later we'll try retracting the wheels at around 450 feet
全靠你们的发动机支撑
and relying on your motors to float the ship.
- 但不要那样做
- Don't try that just yet, though.
- 好的，长官
- Right, sir.
抓住控制杆用力拉，直到你有了坚定的信心了
Now, grab the column and pull her until you feel the inside of your backbone.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
你驾驶过B-25在500英尺内起飞吗？长官
Did you ever take off a B-25 at 500 feet, sir?
没有，但是你们可以别担心
No. But you men will. Don't worry about it.
看看劳森
Watch Lawson there.
你们至少得把发动机转速提到那样高，甚至更高
You'll have to rev your motors at least that high and maybe higher.
大约7oo英尺，他烧掉了他的尾撬，他没有来得及收起轮子
About 700 feet. He burned his tailskid. Didn't pull his wheels up soon enough.
嘿兄弟，刚才的起飞真是虚惊一场啊
Brother, that takeoff was strictly on the cob.
你的飞机真像一只撕碎的鸭子
That airplane of yours looked exactly like a ruptured duck.
你觉得它怎么样？
How do you like this guy?
他起飞就像一个年迈的女士，顶着狂风行行走
He takes off like an old lady in a high wind,
终于鼓起勇气，试试真正的飞机了
and then he's got the nerve to talk about a real ship.
你真走运没有在一个泥泞的机场，不然你还会在这儿
It's lucky you didn't have a muddy field, or you'd still be there.
我一点都不担心那个，你和格雷确实在忸怩作态
If I were you I'd worry about that turkey you and Gray are pushing around the sky.
- 撕裂的“鸭子”一切安好
- The ruptured duck will get along okay.
- 我被侮辱了，走吧，兄弟们
- Oh, I'm insulted. Come on, fellows.
不会修很长时间的，先生
That won't take long to fix, sir.
撕裂的“鸭子”
Ruptured duck.
特德
Ted
如果是个女孩，琳达这个名字怎么样？
Don't you think Linda's a good name, if it's a girl?
哦，好，好，很好
Oh, yes, yes, it's fine.
不，也许是尼古拉，尼古拉
No, maybe Nichola. Nichola?
听起来很悦耳，是吧？
That has a nice sound, don't you think?
什么？对对
What's that? Oh, yes.
亲爱的，我们不要着急，现在就决定吧
Look, honey, we don't have to decide that right now, do we?
不用
No.
特德
Ted.
他伤得不重吧？
He wasn't badly hurt, was he?
- 谁？
- Who?
- 约翰尼.亚当斯
- Johnny Adams.
- 你怎么知道约翰尼的？
- How'd you hear about Johnny?
- 都传开了
- Those things get around.
- 他没有吧？
- He wasn't hurt, was he?
- 当然没有
- Of course not.
我不知道是怎么发生的
I don't know how those things get started.
每个在这个基地打听出来的消息，总要被吹捧一番
Every time a guy does a noseover on this field, it's a crack-up.
特德
Ted
你晚饭后就一直在忙来，我们出去走走
You've been working ever since dinner. Come on, let's get some air.
不错
It's a deal.
真美
Nice.
很抱歉，我们不能有更多的时间在一起，艾伦
I'm sorry we haven't had more time together, Ellen.
我们现在的时间很少,但以后都是我们的
We can spare a little. We've got all the rest of our lives.
对
That's right
什么花开了，好香啊，是吧？
Something blooming? It smells good, doesn't it?
- 特德
- Ted.
- 什么？
- What?
求你了，不要胡思乱想
Please, don't worry about anything.
我没有担心我只是在工作，仅此而己
I'm not worrying, just working, that's all.
你知道，这次的任务非常重要
You know, this is going to be quite a deal.
你不是在担心你的任务，你担心因为你有一个妻子
You're not worried about the deal. You're worried because you've got a wife.
那是错的，特德
And that's wrong, Ted.
鲍勃格雷没有来吓唬你吧？
Say, Bob Gray hasn't been trying to scare you, has he?
- 当然没有
- Of course not.
- 那就好
- Okay.
因为没什么好担心的，没什么
Because there's nothing to worry about, nothing.
傻瓜，我就装作不知道
Silly, as if I didn't know that.
还有，如果发生了什么你会得到政府保险的全部
Besides, if anything did happen, you've got all that government insurance,
这样我就能照顾你和孩子很长一段时间了
that'll take care of you and the baby for a long while.
天哪，我在说什么无论如何也不会发生什么的
Oh, what am I talking about? Nothing's going to happen anyhow.
特德，看着我
Ted, look at me.
孩子和我不需要任何东西，除了你
That baby and I, we won't ever need anything but you.
我们谁都不准害怕，特德
We mustn't either of us be scared about it, Ted.
因为我们的孩子是我坚信你会回来的理由
Because the baby, the baby's why I know you're coming back to us.
这次我们做好一点，不然就再也听不到这样的声音了
We'd better make this one, or Shorty'll never let us hear the last of it.
好
Yeah.
- 听到那些引擎了吗？
- Hear those engines?
- 就像音乐一样
- Like music.
来吧，你们这些有前途的巴土司机
Come on, you hopped up bus drivers.
十个星期以来的一个狂欢夜，来吧
It's been 10 weeks work and one night's fun. Let's go.
- 我把侧翼立起来了，兄弟们
- I got my flaps up, brother.
- 燃烧吧，勇敢者们
- Heat it up there, Smitty boy.
蒸汽的丝丝声你们要去哪？没有人拦你
Steam and sizzle. Where you're going, no one's gonna hold you tight.
嗨，多克，知道怎么跳舞吗？
Hey there, Doc, don't you know how to dance?
当别人拿走你的高射炮时
When they start picking flak out of your feet,
你应该庆幸它会得到更好的利用
you'll wish you'd put them to better use.
我是医生，不是爵士舞迷，肖特
I'm a doctor, not a jitterbug, Shorty.
- 嗨，这是在做什么？
- Hey, what gives?
- 肖特组织的的派对
- Shorty's throwing a party.
派对？为什么？
A party? What for
有人说他是在庆祝得州宪法日
Somebody said he's celebrating Texas Constitution Day.
- 德州宪法日？
- Texas Constitution Day?
- 那么我也得试一下
- Say, I'm gonna sample this.
找个女孩吧，劳森
Grab your gal, Lawson.
不知道今天是山姆.休斯敦的生日吗？
Don't you know it's Sam Houston's birthday?
山姆.休斯敦
Sam Houston?
一个从未到过德州的人，门奇经常说起
For a guy that never saw Texas, that Manch is really sold.
- 你好，劳森
- Hi, Lawson.
- 你好啊，怎么想起这么放荡的？
- Hi. How did this riot get started?
今天是德州加入联邦纪念日
It's Texas Admission Day.
这不是放荡，先生，这是一场已然的战争
And that ain't no riot, mister, that's a full-fledged war.
- 看见艾伦了吗？
- Seen Ellen?
- 我谁都看见过的
- I've seen everybody.
- 你好，飞行员，
- Hello, flyer.
- 和我跳支舞吗
- My dance?
当然啊，我的心上人
All of them, my boy.
此刻起的每一只舞，直至最后
Every dance from now on out, including the last one.
我爱你，斯基
And I love you, Ski.
我爱你，我爱你，我爱你
I love you, I love you, I love you.
这真搞笑劳森以前居然和一架德州飞机…
You know, it's a funny thing. That Lawson used to be about as graceful
一样高雅，快瞧他.
as a Texas steer. Now, look at him.
也许是那个女孩的缘故
Maybe the girl's got something to do with it.
你说上次，克勒文…
Ah, you said it that time, Clever.
有些事我打算告诉你更多
You know, there's something I mean to tell you more often,
- 但我一直没找到机会
- but I never seem to get the chance.
- 什么事？
- What is it?
只是我爱你
Just that I love you.
我今天收到了你母亲的一封信忘了告诉你
I got a letter from your mother this morning. Forgot to tell you.
她说你要自己照顾好自己
She said to take good care of you.
- 那我怎么样
- How am I doing?
- 比母亲曾经梦想的好
- Better than mother ever dreamed of.
好了，好了
Here. Here.
笑一笑，唱啊
Now smile and sing.
特德
Ted.
电话响了
Telephone's ringing.
- 电话，特德
- Telephone, Ted.
- 好的
- Oh, sure.
是吗，现在？好的
Yeah? Right now? Okay.
好
Okay.
行
什么事？
What was it?
是一次夜间召集，但这是一个美妙的夜晚
Oh, just another night call. But what a night.
对不起
I'm sorry.
几点了？
What time is it?
3:10
- 心里难受吗？
- Hung-over maybe a little?
- 没什么，只是头痛病
- Oh, just a headache.
- 我不大适应派对的气氛
- I'm not used to party life.
- 可怜的宝贝
- Poor baby.
你应该睡觉了，我早饭前赶回来
You go to sleep. I'll be back by breakfast time.
我很困了，晚安，亲爱的
I'm so sleepy. Goodnight, darling.
或者说早安
Or rather, good morning.
如果我得到一个假期我要整整睡上六天
Boy, if I ever get a leave, I'm going to sleep for six days solid.
不知道又是什么
I wonder what this is.
各位，你们的飞机检修好了，加满油了，准备起飞
Well, men, your ships are all serviced, gassed, and ready to go.
你们将轮流起飞
You will take off in shifts,
一批45分钟
the first shift taking off in 45 minutes.
约克上校会给你们准飞的指示
Captain York will give you your clearances.
有一件事必须清楚
Now there's one thing that must be thoroughly understood.
今早起飞后
After you take off this morning,
你们不允许见到任何人、和任何人说话打电话
甚至是你们的妻子
you are to see no one, speak to no one, telephone no one, not even your wife.
没有例外
There are no exceptions.
继续你们到达目的地的油耗测试
Continue your gas consumption tests to your destination.
你们的任务要求低空飞行
Now, the work you will be asked to do will require a little low altitude flying,
所以超低空飞行是完全可以的
so hedge-hopping on this trip is perfectly okay.
记住，牛仔们总是戴高帽子
Only bear in mind that cowboys wear pretty tall hats,
所以小心一点，就这样
so watch your step, men. That's all.
我想你们已经为你们自愿参加的任务作好了准备
I think you're very well prepared for what you volunteered to do
我要感谢你们辛勤而出色的表现
and I want to thank you for a lot of good hard work.
几天后我们再见，祝你们好运
I'll see you in a few days. Good luck.
我想找个机会和艾伦说再见
I hope I get a chance to tell Ellen goodbye.
你会有的
Yeah, you will.
你们的目的地是阿拉梅达空军基地
Your destination is Alameda field.
走南方航线在圣安东尼奥补给然后前进
Take the southern route, refuel at San Antonio and march.
点到名后就可以开始了。第一个，霍尔斯通
As your names are called you can start. First flight, Holstrom,
琼斯 劳森，第二个
Jones, Lawson. Second flight...
- 特德
- Ted.
- 好了，宝贝，我们要出发了
- Well, this is it, honey. We're off.
- 什么时候？
- How soon?
- 只有时间收收东西了
- Just got time to pack.
我的B-4包在哪里？
Where's my B-4 bag?
- 在壁橱里，我去拿
- In the closet. I'll get it.
- Good.
- 好的
袜子、衬衣
Socks, shirts.
- 我的领带也在壁橱？
- My ties in the closet?
- 是的，我去拿
- Yes, I have them.
好的
Good.
哇，不要光着脚走进去，我打碎了个杯子
Wow! Don't go in there in your bare feet, I broke a glass.
好的
All right.
- 你忘了你的牙刷
- You forgot your toothbrush.
- 哦，见鬼
- Oh, doggone it.
- 都收好了吗？
- We got everything?
- 差不多了
- I think so.
好样的
Swell.
好的，做一个好女孩，照顾好孩子
Well, be a good girl and take good care of that baby.
- 我会的，特德
- I will, Ted.
- 也照顾好你自己
- Yourself, too.
特德，你走后的每一天，我都会给你写一封信
Oh, Ted, I'm going to write you a letter every day you're gone,
我知道他们不会送达，我也不会寄出的
I know they won't deliver them. I won't even mail them.
但我还是要写这样我们就能保持联系了
But I'm going to write just the same.That way, we'll kind of be in touch.
我们就能感觉到彼此的呼吸
That way, we'll feel close.
再见
Goodbye.
再见，飞行员
Bye, flyer.
告诉我甜心，为什么你这么可爱？
Tell me, honey. How come you're so cute?
我找到了一个如此帅气的小伙子我必须得这样啊
I had to be if I was gonna get such a good looking fellow.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
嘿，海湾大桥正从我们的右侧离开
Hey, the Bay Bridge is off to our right.
The Bay Bridge is off to our right.
海湾大桥，从它下面飞过怎样？
The Bay Bridge? How about flying under it?
- 为什么？
- For why?
- 那样的话我可以照些照片
- Well, so I can get some pictures.
从下往上拍摄这些超级建筑
You know, shooting up at the superstructure.
- 来吧，劳森
- Come on, Lawson.
- 不想吗？
- Do you want to?
- 好的，听你的，如果我可以让他高兴
- Sure. Go ahead, if it'll make him happy.
- Thanks.
- 谢谢
希望那个跨度里没有缆绳
I hope there are no cables hanging under that span.
我们上吧
Here we go.
让我们轮流来一次，我忘了放胶卷了
Let's take a turn and go it again. I forgot to put film in.
我们要去基地别忘了
We're due at the field. Forget it.
我再也不想试了
Oh, I may never get another crack at it.
嘿，快看
Hey, look.
麦克卢尔，看下面
McClure, take a look down there.
- 是航空母舰
- It's a carrier.
- 是啊，你看他的甲板
- Yeah. And look at her deck.
B-25的，神圣烟雾就是它了
B-25's. Holy Smoke. Then this is it.
有点小，是吧？
Kind of small, isn't she?
- 飞行员呼叫投弹手
- Pilot to bombardier. Pilot
- 飞行员呼叫炮手
- to gunner. Pilot to gunner.
撒切尔、撒切尔
Thatcher. Thatcher.
又断了
It's dead again.
到达以后，我们最后给杜利德报告一下
We'd better report it to Doolittle when we get in.
对，还有左引擎对你来说还那样讨厌吗？
Yeah, that left engine along with it. Still seem a little rough to you?
我不想说了
I can't tell anymore.
- 你们的飞机没事吧？
- Is everything okay on your ship?
- 什么？没事没事，长官
- Why, yes, sir, yes, sir.
出租车已经在航母码头了，他们会照顾好你们的
Taxi over to the edge of the carrier's wharf. They'll take care of you there.
好的，长官
Yes, sir.
他们也不等人家下车
They don't even wait until a fellow gets out.
- 所有的海军都是这样自以为是
- All Navy guys are cocky.
- 米勒就是海军
- Miller's a Navy guy.
米勒其实不是海军，他是飞行员
Well, Miller isn't exactly Navy. He's a pilot.
喂，飞行员
Hey, Spike.
- 飞行员
- Spike.
- 飞行员 什么事？
- Spike, what's the matter?
我在抱怨我的燃油泵
Oh, I put in a beef about my fuel pump
杜利德叫我把它送到飞机修理棚去
and Doolittle told me to take her to the hangar.
你不去？
Well, then you're not going?
不去，其实飞机没什么毛病
No, and there's nothing really wrong with that plane.
- 这是我们中队最好的飞机
- It's the best ship in the squad.
- 兄弟，别大意
- Boy, that's rough.
正准备告诉他用我们的对讲机
And I nearly told him about our interphone.
你真是个无可救药的人
You would've been a cooked goose.
我也觉得我去看看那些海军
I think, sir, I'll go and watch those Navy guys.
- 他们会摔坏的
- They might bang her up or something.
- 想得不错
- That's a good idea.
你觉得呢？
How do you like that?
他们肯定会把“鸭子”弄坏
They're going to break the Duck's back sure.
我们怎么从那些海军手里弄到离合器
How did we get in the clutches of these Navy guys anyhow?
- 你们看，这真是一艘大船
- Boy, that's an awful big ship.
- 是的，去看看
- Yeah, let's take a look at her.
- 再见，飞行员
- So long, Spike.
- Be seeing you, Spike.
- 再见，伙计们
- Goodbye, fellows.
劳森中尉，报到，长官
Lieutenant Lawson, reporting aboard, sir.
- 伯廷勒，把劳森中尉带到…
- Bettinger, take Lieutenant Lawson to...
- 306，长官
- 306, sir.
- 306
- 这边走，长官
- This way, sir.
待会见
See you guys later.
- 麦克卢尔中尉，报到，长官
- Lieutenant McClure, reporting aboard, sir.
- 这些是你的住处，长官
- These are your quarters, sir.
这是你们的住处，长官
These are your quarters, sir.
怀特和费尔顿先生正在上岸假期中
Mr. White and Mr. Felton are on shore leave.
谢谢
Thank you.
你确定能找到回到甲板的路吗，长官？
Are you sure you'll be able to find your way back up to the deck, sir?
哦，是的，谢谢
Oh, sure. Thanks.
你在做什么？
What are you doing down here?
随便逛逛，你在做什么呢？
Oh, just looking around. What are you doing here?
随便逛逛
Just looking around.
- 你也迷路了
- Are you lost too?
- 是吗？我就像一只被逮住的老鼠
- Am I lost? I'm trapped like a rat.
我已经走了几英里了
I've been walking for miles.
这是我见过的最大的船
This is the biggest cockeyed ship I've ever seen.
是啊，我希望甲板能有两倍这么大
Yeah. And I wish the deck was twice as big.
吸烟灯已灭，吸烟灯已灭
The smoking lamp is out. The smoking lamp is out.
长官，吸烟灯已灭，意思是船上禁止吸烟
Sir, "The smoking lamp is out" means no smoking anywhere on the ship.
- 好的
- Okay.
- 为什么？
- Why is that?
因为正在补给燃料，长官，他们会告诉我们什么时候结束
Because they're refueling, sir. They'll let us know when they're through.
你好
Hello.
哟！你们终于来了
Well, you guys finally got on, huh?
对，我们在看看这个浴盆
Yeah, we've just been looking the tub over.
- 你们住得怎样？
- How are your quarters?
- 很不错
- Perfect.
有两个铺位和帆布床
Nice room with two bunks and a cot.
帆布床，跟我来，兄弟们，我让你们看看真正的房间
A cot? Follow me, brothers. I'm gonna show you real quarters.
我是说寝室
And I mean quarters.
帽子 帽子
Hats. Hats.
- 看，这是什么？
- Well, look at what's here.
- 我们有客人来了
- Well, we have guests.
为什么把大家从棚户租赁区赶到这儿？
What's the idea of bringing people up here from the tenement district?
这里被戏谑地叫做“旗舰舱”
This is jocularly known as the admiral's cabin.
你们的洗澡时间快到了
Looks like you guys are going to have to start bathing.
还没完呢，还有其他的，跟我走
This isn't all. There's something else. Follow me.
非常乐意
I'd be glad to.
请当心那些地毯
Careful of the rugs, please.
里面的东西，先生们，可以让你们大饱眼福
Now just inside, gentlemen, is something to really feast your peepers on.
晚饭后第一个回来的人才有机会看到
The first guy turns in after dinner gets this bed for the trip.
你知道是谁吗？进来
You know who that'll be. Enter.
哪来的又脏又恶心的…快滚蛋，你这个橡皮虫
What dirty, lowlife... Come out of there, you boll weevil!
好吧，那给我吃玉米让我快快长大
Well, feed me corn and watch me grow.
这些渣滓是怎么进来的？
How did all this scum get in?
我是在一张海军帆布床
And me in an Army cot.
今晚结束你死定了
That's where he'll end up, before the night's over.
- 我们走
- Let's get out of here.
- 噢，上尉
- Oh, Lieutenant!
你们去吃晚饭时
When you guys go down to dinner,
能带给我一份半熟的烤牛肉三明治…
would you mind bringing back a roast beef sandwich, rare,
和一份橘子派吗，上尉？
and a piece of huckleberry pie, Lieutenant.
- 现在你还觉得来这里不错吗？
- Well, are you still glad you came along?
- 当然，你不是吗？
- Sure. Aren't you
我的这回的任务感觉怪怪的
I've got a funny feeling about this job.
我觉得可能事情没有我们想象的那样有把握
I think maybe it isn't going to be as much of a cinch as we figured on.
我也这样想过
Yeah, I've been thinking the same thing.
我的飞机在那里，我们去看看吧
Well, my ship's over there. I think I'll go take a look at it.
- 鸭子，在上面
- Well, the Duck's up ahead.
- 明早见
- I'll see you in the morning.
- 晚安
- Goodnight.
是谁？
Who's that?
- 是你吗，撒切尔？
- That you, Thatcher?
- 是的，长官
- Oh, yes, sir
算了吧，撒切尔
Oh, forget it, Thatcher.
这些东西拴紧了吧？
Got her pretty well lashed down, haven't they?
是的，他们干得不
Yes, sir. They did a good job.
我有点担心它
I was kind of worried about her,
所以我想上去看看它
so I thought I'd better come up and have a look.
你寂寞吗？
You lonesome?
我想大家都有点，长官
I guess everybody is a little, sir.
不要让领导操心，戴维，你的住处还不错吧？
Don't bother with the sirs, Dave. Your quarters all right?
- 是的，很好
- Yeah. Fine.
- 伙食也很好，不是吗？
- Grub's good, too, isn't it?
很长时间都没吃到这么好了
The best I've had in a long time, sir.
当我们回家后有什么打算吗，撒切尔？
What are you going to do when we get back home, Thatcher?
我在比令斯有个女孩，长官，如果能回去我会和她结婚
Oh, I have a girl in Billings, sir. I'm going to marry her, if we get back.
我们会平安返回的
Oh, we'll get back all right.
你好
Oh, hello.
- 你好
- Hello.
我本来想上来拍几张星星的，但雾太大了
I thought I'd come up and shoot the stars for a little while, but I guess it's too foggy.
太多雾了，确实
Pretty foggy, all right.
- 你们在这儿做什么？
- What are you guys doing here?
- 就是想呼吸点新鲜空气
- Oh, just getting a little air.
- 是啊，下面太无聊了
- Yeah, it's pretty stuffy down below.
- 的确如此
- Yeah, it sure is.
你们这些人还担心这个撕裂的鸭子，就像一群老处女一
样
You guys worry over the ruptured duck like a bunch of old maids.
我想睡觉了
Me, I'm going to bed.
- 晚安
- Goodnight.
晚安，特德
Goodnight, Ted.
空气不错，是吧？
Wonderful air, isn't it?
吸烟灯己亮，吸烟灯己亮
The smoking lamp is lit. The smoking lamp is lit.
- 怎么了？发生什么了？
- What's wrong? What happened?
- 吹的是各就各位号
- Just battle stations.
日落和日出的时候，这个大家伙总会给我们惹麻烦
Around sunup and sundown the pig boats give us a little trouble
所以我们总是静静等它
so we always lay for them.
这是吉格.怀特，这是巴德.费尔顿
This is Jig White and I'm Bud Felton.
- 很高兴见到你
- Glad to see you.
- 你好
- How are you?
- 待会见
- See you later.
- 我们是在航行中吗？
- Are we underway?
- 还有5个小时
- For the last five hours.
很高兴和你同住，旱鸭子
Glad to have you aboard, Army.
总部命令各战位备战
General Quarters, man your battle stations.
陆军人员，请准备你们的飞机
Army personnel, man your planes.
小子，你们唯一可以逃离这里的方式是找一个起重机
Boy, the only way you're going to get that thing off of here is with a crane.
也许是，但我也在想我们可以借助自己的力量起飞
Maybe so. But we kind of think we can take off on our own power.
嘿，他们打哪儿来？
Hey, where'd they come from?
他们是护卫舰
That's what's known as an escort.
晚上他们已经跟着我们了
They just slipped up on us during the night.
海军总爱秘密行事
The Navy likes to do things quietly.
好像就要有一场表演似的，是吧？
Looks like it's really going to be a show, doesn't it?
我今天真不想让我离开床单，那张床太舒服了
Boy, did I hate to part skin from sheet this morning. What a bed.
对了，这是肖特.门奇、吉格.怀特和巴德.费尔顿
Oh, this is Shorty Manch. Jig White and Bud Felton
- 您好
- Hello
- 嗨，你们好
- Hi y'all.
他们很幸运可以不在“船舰舱“里睡党
This lucky stiff is sleeping in the bedroom off the admiral's cabin.
是啊，住得很棒，就是无所事事
Yeah. Wonderful accommodations, but nothing much to do.
我觉得至少应该来点纸牌或是其他什么游戏
I thought there'd at least be a poker game or something going on.
我想他们时不时会玩的
Oh, I guess they have them every once in a while.
“七趾皮特”呢？你们这儿玩吗？
How about Seven-Toed Pete? Do you ever play much of that around here?
什么“七趾皮特”？
What's Seven-Toed Pete?
这是一种七张牌的游戏
Well, it's a kind of seven-card poker.
- 我有时间会教你们
- I'd be glad to teach it to you some time.
- 从未听说过
- Never heard of it.
注意
Attention, Army personnel!
陆军人员注意，在守卫室集合
Attention, Army personnel! Assemble in Ward Room.
全军注意，在守卫室集合
- 待会见，各位
- See you later, fellows.
大家好，很荣幸见到大家，我们很快就会在一起了
Well, it's been a great pleasure, fellows.We'll certainly have to get together soon.
也许我们可以玩那个扑克游戏了
Maybe we can get up that little game of poker.
待会见
See you later.
我相信他很爱玩那个扑克游戏
You know, I believe that boy wants to play poker.
我在想他是不是上船前带足了钱的
I wonder if they got their pay before they came aboard.
请坐
As you were.
你们不是还有剩下的疑虑吗？
For the benefit of those who haven't already guessed,
我们正在前往日本
we're going straight to Japan.
海军会把我们送到距离日本本土400英里的地方
The Navy will take us within 400 miles of the Japanese mainland.
我们会袭击日本的东京、横滨
We're going to bomb Tokyo, Yokohama,
神户、大阪、名古屋
Kobe, Osaka, Nagoya.
这将是一次夜间行动
It'll be a night job and
你们可以选择你们想去的地方
you will be given the opportunity of choosing the city you prefer.
现在的处境很困难
Now, this is going to be a tight squeeze.
中国军队准备在日占领区开辟小规模战场
The Chinese have prepared small fields just outside of Japanese occupied territory
我们则在空袭后登陆
for us to land on after the raid.
他们会给我们补给然后我们飞往重庆
They'll gas us up and we'll take off for Chungking.
现在起我们将会处在敌人不断攻击的危险中
From now on we're in constant danger of enemy attack.
如果发生地面攻击
If there should be a surface attack,
站在你们的飞机旁，带着灭火器
stand by your planes with fire extinguishers
让海军去对付他们
and let the Navy handle it.
如果发生了空中攻击起飞飞向最近的陆地
If there should be an attack by air, take off and make for the nearest land.
海军会提供导航信息，两天一次
The Navy will give all navigators their bearings twice a day.
再有就是，我还要强调…
Now once more, I want to emphasize that if...
如果有人觉得无法胜任此次任务完全可以自动请退
If any of you feel you're not up to this job, it's perfectly all right for you to drop out.
我们有一些后备人员，他们可以填补你们的位置
We have a few spare men and I think we can fill your place.
约克上校会告诉你们用飞机来干什么
Get together with Captain York and find out what to do with your planes.
明天下午2:30我们再见
We'll meet here tomorrow afternoon at 2:30.
还有问题吗？
Are there any questions?
上校，集合时可以抽烟吗？
Colonel, do you mind if we smoke during these assemblies?
如果海军不反对，我没有异议，还有什么吗？
I have no objection to that if the Navy hasn't. Anything else?
解散
Dismissed.
48、49、50
51、52、53、54
55、56…对不起，门奇
55, 56... Oh, sorry, Manch.
- 只是简单活动一下
- Just getting a little exercise.
- 是吗？我可没有
- Yeah? Well, I wasn't.
我在划分这个巨大的甲板
I'm measuring off this cockeyed deck.
9…
全员注意，你们很想知道我们此次任务的情况
Attention, all personnel. You have been wondering about the mission we are on.
我想你们肯定知道
I think you might like to know
大黄蜂号正开赴日本准备轰炸
that the Army personnel on the Hornet are going to bomb Japan.
我们海军将要把他们送达离敌人最近的地方
We of the Navy are going to take them in as close to the enemy as possible.
这是我们大家的机会
This is a chance for all of us
给日本人一点颜色看看
to give the Japs a dose of their own medicine.
这是一场空海军表演
It's an Army-Navy show.
让我们真诚欢迎这些将士们
Let's extend every courtesy to the Army men on the Hornet
他们将执行这次的任务
who are going to do the job.
祝好运，多多杀敌
Good luck, good hunting
但愿上帝保佑我们这次行动
and may God speed us on our mission.
来点
Have some?
谢谢，伙计
Thanks, buddy.
从没听说过“七趾皮特”玩成这样已经很运气了
You're awfully lucky for guys who never heard of Seven-Toed Pete.
他们告诉我佛吉尼亚也很适合打猎
They tell me Virginia's a great hunting country, too.
是吗？对，我们来玩，小伙子们
What's that? Oh, yeah. Let's play, fellows.
- 赌多少？
- What's the bet?
- 随便你，门奇
- It's up to you, Manch.
他们不是说佛吉尼亚是“总统之乡”吗？
Don't they call Virginia the Mother of Presidents?
对，我是说…赌5个吧
Yeah. I mean... Bet five.
跟10个
Up ten.
托马斯.杰佛逊住在那里吧？
Thomas Jefferson lived there, too, didn't he?
我放弃
很多人都住那里
A lot of guys lived there.
你们确信没玩过“七趾皮特”吗？
Are you sure you never played Seven-Toed Pete before?
10个，你的门奇
Makes it ten to you, Manch.
你们那儿的十二指肠病得到控制了吗？
Have they finally gotten that hookworm situation under control down there?
佛吉尼亚从来没有十二指肠病
There never has been a case of hookworm in Virginia.
- 我是一个对对福
- I've got a small straight.
- 我是清一色
- Mine's seven to the jack.
我是清对
All pink.
我又输了，我想睡觉了
Well, that beats. I think I'll turn in.
- 有人赢了很多钱
- Somebody's won a lot of dough.
- 一点点
- A little.
- 你的牌不好，门奇
- You just had a run of bad cards, Manch.
- 是啊
- Yeah.
我们以后再来玩
What say we get together again pretty soon?
当然，回头见
Oh, sure. See you later.
门奇，你在佛吉尼亚没有什么书吧？
Say, you haven't got any books on Virginia, have you, Manch?
你们陆军都是一群鸽子，我真想你在海军
You Army guys are real pigeons. I wish you were in the Navy.
你去睡我的地方，劳森，我想睡你这儿，如果你不介意
You take the bunk, Lawson. I'll sleep here, if you don't mind.
- 这是什么主意？
- What's the idea?
- 那里有如羽毛般舒适柔软？
- That thing's as soft as a feather bed.
但我可睡不安稳
I never could sleep in it.
- 不赖啊
- Yeah. It's not bad
- 谢谢
- Thanks. Thanks a lot.
兰德尔上尉会告诉我们―些关于航母起飞的事项
Lieutenant Randall is going to tell us something about a carrier takeoff.
兰德尔先生
Mr. Randall.
从你们上飞机开始，我开始负责
From the minute you're in your planes, I'm the man to watch.
当你前一个人准备滑行时请尽快关掉引擎
Have your engines turning over as soon as the man in front of you starts taxiing.
当我要你们加快转速时我会给你们这个标志
When I want you to rev up, I'll give you this.
现在，如果你们的引擎运作得对我来说不好的话
Now, if your engines don't sound right to me,
我会要你们加大引擎转速，时间比你们认为的要长一些
I may have to keep you revved up longer than you
我会来听你们的引擎，然后告诉你什么时候是最佳时机
I can hear your engines and tell when they're missing better than you can.
当我要你开始滑行时，我会给你这个标志
When I want you to start taxiing, I'll give you this.
然后你们就位我会给你们最后一次
Now you're in position. I give you a final rev.
然后我挥下它，你们就起飞
And when I drop it, you're off.
我们会让你们直飞日本，还有一件事
We'll aim you straight for Japan. One more thing.
一旦我们列队起飞
Once we're lined up for the takeoffs,
就不会有延误
there can be no delays.
如果你们的飞机停了没有立即起飞
If your plane stalls, if it doesn't start immediately,
如果你们有任何种类的任何麻烦
if you have any trouble of any kind,
我们将没有时间去处理
we won't have time to do anything about it.
舰桥会按照命令催促你们离舰
The Navy crew has orders to push the ship overboard
给下一架飞机让路
and make way for the next one.
尤里卡中尉有城市和具体目标的详尽地图和照片
Lieutenant Jurika has detailed maps and pictures of cities and specified targets.
尤里卡先生在日本生活了很长的时间
Mr. Jurika spent a great many years in Japan.
我想他可以给我们很多东西
I think it might be a good idea if he gave you some idea
关于我们要对付的那些人
of what kind of people you're going to run up against
以防你们被击落
in case you're forced down.
尤里卡先生
Mr. Jurika.
我是驻日海军助理随员
I was Assistant Naval Attaché at our embassy in Japan,
有很长一段时间了解东方各国的经历
long enough to learn a few things about the Orient.
我们应该怎么做，尤里卡先生？
Just what should we do, Mr. Jurika?
我们应该怎么和那些人相处？一旦我们掉在了日本
How should we conduct ourselves in case we are forced down over Japan?
我的建议是不要让自己掉在了日本
My advice is, see that you're not forced down over Japan.
我为你们设计的路线是从这里开始
The run I've got figured out for you starts here.
这些烟囱是鲜红的砖石做的，你们一定能找到
The smokestacks are bright red brick, and you can't miss them.
日本最大的冶炼厂之一
One of the largest smelters in Japan.
然后沿着海岸线每十秒投一次弹
Then, following the line of the bay and allowing 10 seconds between bombs
你们必须清除这个和这个
you should take out this and this.
一次性轰炸这两座机械工厂
Both of them are machine shops owned by brothers,
我忘了叫什么名字，但我记得我不喜欢它们
I forget their names but I remember I didn't like them.
然后在这里你们开始丢燃烧弹，你们是怎么列队的，劳森
Then on out here to drop your incendiary. How does this line up for you, Lawson?
好，你去投掷燃烧弹，克勒文
Well, you're going to drop them, Clever.
我觉得路线不错，希望你们也这样认为
The run seems all right for me if it's okay for you.
- 我们可以完成任务
- We can take them out.
- 很好
- Fine.
琼斯，你们有针对这种路线的训练吗？
Jones, have you got the course laid out for this run?
好，到这边来，小伙子
Yes. Over here, fellows.
你们从这里起飞，往东京的正西方行驶
Now you'll take off about here. You go due west to Tokyo
以最小巡行航速，大约50英尺高度
at minimum cruising speed, flying at about 50 feet.
到达海岸线，上升到1500英尺
When you hit the bay, get up to about 1,500 feets
完成轰炸后下降，离开陆地
complete your bombing run, then down again and out to sea,
- 屋久岛南偏东南方向
- south by southeast to Yakushima.
- 我们能带上地图吗？
- Can we take the maps with us?
需要的都可以拿上,上面没有作任何标注
All you need. Be sure there are no marks on them though,
因为如果你们被捕 可能会泄露你们从哪儿来
which might show the Japs where you came from in case you're captured.
另外我给第一架飞机加了4个燃烧弹
By the way, I'm taking off first with four incendiaries.
这样东京就能为你们美丽燃烧
That should light up Tokyo pretty well for you.
我们到了中国降落场会不会被日本占领了？
Suppose by the time we get to China, the Japs have taken over the landing field?
一旦被日本占领了
if the Japs have captured it.
你们到达机场时中国方面会给你们发送信号
The Chinese will arrange a signal for you when you get to the field
如果你们一直飞行，最后燃料用尽
If that's the case you've got to keep right on going until you've run out of gas
然后跳伞离机，然后把飞机毁掉
then bail out and destroy your planes.
是的
Yes.
东京上空的阻塞气球，部署上有些变化
There's just been a change in the disposition
这个气球和这个
This balloon and this one
今早被移到这里和这里
were moved this morning to here and here.
你知道，这些气球的变化把我弄晕了
You know, the changes in those balloons threw me.
就象一个整天在浴缸里汗流浃背的人一样
Just think, a bunch of guys sweating all day in a sub
沿着东京湾走来走去
down under Tokyo bay, guys just like us
晚上偷偷摸摸打听气球的位置
sneaking up at night to radio balloon positions.
只是让我听到任何人谈论海军
Just let me hear anybody talk about the Navy again.
他们很不错
Boy, they're good.
非常不错，扑克也打得不错
Plenty. They're not bad at poker either.
你又在说笑
Oh, you're not kidding.
我盼望在重庆给艾伦什么礼物
I kind of figured on getting Ellen a present in Chungking, you know,
和服或者什么
a kimono or something.
但这些海军把我的钱赢光了
But these Navy guys have cleaned me.
信不信由你，我只剩14美元了
Believe it or not, I've only got 14 bucks.
我也只有8或者10美元能给你了
Well, I got $8 or $10 I could let you have.
哦！不，不，我也是想想而已
Oh, no. No. I've been thinking,
这里一包香烟卖60美分
cigarettes sell for 60 cents a carton on the boat here.
但在重庆我听说有人愿意出7美元
But in Chungking, I hear the boys will pay seven bucks.
是吗？
Yeah?
所以我准备在“鸭子”上装满棺材钉
So I figure I may loadthe duck with coffin nails.
这个主意不错
Hey, that's an idea.
- 今晚真不错
- It's a good night for subs.
- 是啊
- Yeah.
这真有意恩
You know, it's funny.
小时候，我总是梦想去船上看看
When I was a kid I used to dream about going someplace on a ship.
现在我在船上了
Well, here I am.
正开往日本
And out there is Japan.
我母亲曾经有一个日本园丁
My mother had a Jap gardener once.
他看起来很不错就是矮点
He seemed like a nice little guy.
你知道，我并不恨日本人
You know, I don't hate Japs, yet.
是有点意思，我不喜欢他们但也不恨
It's a funny thing. I don't like them, but I don't hate them.
我想我也是，这种感觉很复杂
I guess I don't either.You get kind of mixed up.
是的
Yeah.
这很难琢磨，但毕竟我们来了
It's hard to figure. Yet here we are.
我最想成为一个航空工程师
All I ever wanted to be was an aeronautical engineer.
我40岁参军因为我觉得这是最好的学习机会
I joined the Army in '40 because I figured it was the best way to learn.
我不仇恨任何人
I wasn't sore at anybody.
但突然你就要意识到你要把一吨多的烈性炸药
But here you suddenly realize you're going to drop
投放到世界上最大的城市之
a ton of high explosives on one of the biggest cities in the world.
你有点敏感吧？
You're not getting squeamish, are you?
不不，当然不是
Oh, no, of course not.
我并不掩饰我对杀害众多平民的厌恶
I don't pretend to like the idea of killing a bunch of people
但如果我不把炸弹丢在他们头上
but it's the case of drop a bomb on them
不久他们就会丢在艾伦头上
or pretty soon they'll be dropping one on Ellen.
对啊
Yeah, that's right.
我在想到底有多少人能最后挺过来
I wonder how many of us will pull through.
哦，他们估计一半
Oh, they figure about half.
- 每个人都认为自己是一半当中的一个
- And everybody thinks he'll be in that half.
- 对
- Yeah.
- 你什么时候结婚，鲍勃？
- When are you going to get married, Bob?
- 当我找到艾伦那样好的姑娘的时候
- Oh, when I find somebody like Ellen.
这真好，你知道，就是我们四个
It'd be swell, you know. The four of us.
一切都结束后，我会买一个小农场
You know, when this is over I'd like to get me a small ranch.
养上四、五十头牛什么的
Something that'd run about 40 or 50 head of cattle.
一口好井，一间好房，这是给孩子们的
A nice well and a house. It'd be wonderful for kids.
我对农场真的很感兴趣
I've always been kind of nuts about ranches myself.
你知道吗？在好年景，你可以自己丰衣足食
You know, in a decent year you can make real dough
可以吃得饱饱的而且还有40头牛啊
out of 40 head of cattle, if you've got feed.
- 我们为什么不去干干那些
- Why don't we do something like that?
- 你去的话那我也去
- Well, I'm game if you are.
- 好的，就这么说定了
- Okay, it's a deal.
- 好
- Good.
当然，如果我们有80头牛的话我们就可以大干一场
Of course, now if we had 80 head of cattle we'd really have ourselves a layout.
- 是啊，我们自己产的肉
- Yeah, and our own meat too.
- 还有，牛奶、黄油、鸡蛋
- Oh, yeah, milk, butter, eggs,
所有的一切
the whole works.
一个有自己一隅的人
You know, a guy who's got himself a place,
他是不会忧虑什么的
he doesn't have to worry about anything.
- 在附近打猎
- And with a little hunting near.
- 哦，当然，那很容易
- Oh, sure, that's easy.
天哪，战争结束，我高兴得快疯了
Gosh, I'll be glad when this war ends.
紧急情况时，就不会有集合
In the event of an emergency there will be no assembly.
没有最后指示，我们立即就起飞
No last minute instructions. We'll just take off.
离开“大黄蜂号”半小时内出现发动机故障
If you should develop motor trouble within a half hour after leaving the Hornet,
请飞回船舰，并在水面降落
fly back to the ship and land in the water.
海军会把你们捞出来
The Navy will try to fish you out.
如果是半小时后发生了什么问题，你就得带着继续前进
If trouble should develop after that time, you'll have to keep right on going.
因为那时候战舰就要向敌方开火了
Because by that time the fleet will have to fire on any craft overhead.
我不希望你们用完备用燃料罐后马上扔掉
I don't want you to throw out the extra cans of gas as you use them.
那样会给日本日留下追踪“大黄蜂号”的线索
That would leave a perfect trail for the Japs to follow back to the Hornet.
把罐子积攒起来，一次全部扔掉
Save the cans and throw them all out at one time.
现在，我再重申一下我前面说的
Now let me repeat something I've said previously.
你们负责轰炸指定的军事目标，除此之外别无它物
You are to bomb the military targets assigned to you and nothing else.
当然，在这样的任务过程中不可能不伤及平民
Of course, in an operation of this kind you cannot avoid killing civilians.
因为战争机器是被公民操纵的
Because war plants are manned by civilians.
如果你们有对这种必要的伤亡有任何道德情感
If any of you have any moral feelings about this necessary killing,
如果你把自己当作一个谋杀者的话
if you feel that you might think of yourself afterward as a murderer,
我希望你能离开，我们会找人代替你
I want you to drop out. We'll find someone to take your place.
我保证没有人能指责你的这种情感
And I promise you that no one will blame you for your feelings.
除非计划有变，否则我们明晚起飞
Barring any sudden switch in plans, we'll take off tomorrow night.
还有一件事
There's one thing more.
当我们在重庆相聚时我们会安排一场派对
When we meet in Chungking I'm going to throw you a party
这样你们也可以和你们的孙子们提起…
that you can tell your grandchildren about.
你们是好样的，和你们在一起我感到骄檄
You're a great bunch of guys. I'm proud to be associated with you.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
- 12条香烟
- 12 cartons of cigarettes.
- 12条
- 12 cartons?
陆军都发了什么了？
Say, what gives with the Army?
我从未卖过这么多的香烟
I've never sold so many cigarettes in my life.
- 我们是烟鬼
- We're chain smokers.
- 你是在吃烟，要什么牌的？
- You must eat them. What kind will it be?
随便吧
Oh, any kind.
- 你只是想要很多烟
- You just want lots of cigarettes.
- 你猜对了
- You hit it right on the head.
好吧
All right.
共7.20美元
That'll be $7.20.
我们的航母特遣部队已经被敌方水面舰队发现
Now hear this. Our carrier task force has been sighted by enemy surface vessels.
所有陆军飞行员准备好你们的飞机
All Army pilots and crews, man your planes for immediate takeoff.
不到3分钟我们就能看见日本人了
There goes a Jap just three minutes after we sighted her.
它有2分钟的时间告诉东京它看见了什么
Yeah. That means she had two minutes to tell Tokyo what she saw.
注意命令，赶紧装上炸弹
Now hear this. Get all bombs loaded on the double.
- 你们都准备好了吗？
- Are you all packed?
- 准备好5天了，长官
- Have been for five days, sir.
好的，看看其他人怎么对付“鸭子”的吧
Good. Better watch how those guys handle the Duck.
是的，长官
I will, sir.
不要告诉其他人小炮塔的事
And don't tell anybody about that bumped turret.
我不会的，长官
I won't, sir.
- 我们要走了
- Hey, we're off, aren't we?
- 耶
- Yeah!
哦，快炸烂他
Oh, bomb me, daddy!
我想所有的东西都准备好了
I think I've got everything packed.
- 太好了，谢谢
- Swell, thanks.
- 很抱歉，没我们没有
- I'm sorry we couldn't have
准备一个好的天气给你们
picked out a little better weather for you.
- 我们会成功的，再会，费尔顿
- We'll make it. So long, Felton.
- 狠狠揍他们一拳让他们记住
- Give them a pasting they'll never forget.
我们会的，谢谢你们做的一切
We will. Look, thanks for everything.
你们海军，你很好，再会了
You guys in the Navy, well, you're okay. Be seeing you.
注意命令，到飞行甲板检查，发动引擎
Now hear this. Clear the flight deck to start engines.
嘿，找我的钱呢？
Hey, how about my change?
他们给了我们15罐燃料油而不是10罐
They're giving us fifteen extra cans instead of ten.
很好，至少现在起飞能让我们在白天到达东京
Good. At least getting off now will put us over Tokyo in daylight.
白天不用担心阻塞气球
Don't forget about the barrage balloons in daylight too.
下次你就会告诉我不用担心了
Oh, next you'll be telling me it's good
因为白天你就可以照到照片了
because you can get better pictures in the daytime.
- 你没开玩笑吧？
- You're not kidding about that, either.
- 让我们再检查一下
- Let's give her a final check.
嘿，鲍勃
Hey, Bob.
- 什么？
- What?
- 你在前面吗？
- Are you up ahead?
四号场地
Fourth spot.
重庆见
See you in Chungking.
你说的，兄弟
You said it, brother.
- 他们怎么样，杜利德？
- How they doing?
- 随时都可以起飞
- Doolittle will be off any second.
然后是胡佛、霍尔斯通、格雷然后戴维.琼斯，我们第七个
Then Hoover, Holstrom, Gray and Davey Jones, we're seventh.
7是幸运的数字
Seven's a lucky number.
嘿，特德，把这个带上好吗？
Ted, Ted. Hey, Ted, Ted, hey. Put these some place, will you?
- 这是什么？
- What are they?
- 唱片
- Sizzle platters.
我已经装了一个留声机了，但我们没有地方放唱片
I've got the phonograph in my ship. But I haven't got room for the records.
我们重庆见，跳中国的摇摆舞
We'll meet in Chungking and cut a Chinese rug.
好的，肖特
Okay, Shorty.
- 收好它们，麦克卢尔
- Take care of these, will you, McClure?
- 好的
- Right.
- 飞行员呼叫炮手
- Pilot to gunner.
- 炮手回复飞行员，请讲，长官
- Gunner to pilot. Go ahead, sir.
如果有机会注意看一眼小炮塔
Take a look at the turret if you get a chance.
我一直在看，长官，但还是很乱
I've been working on that, sir. She's still jammed.
如果需要就用辅助燃料
We'll use the auxiliary power if we have to.
好的，长官
Right, sir.
我们把自己弄得一团糟，是不是，劳森？
We've got ourselves in a fine jam, haven't we, Lawson?
现在说这些时机真好啊
Well, this is a great time to think of that.
不是，我是说提前起飞
Oh, no, I mean having to take off ahead of schedule.
对不起，达文波特，我想我有点紧张了吧
Oh, I'm sorry, Davenport. I guess maybe I'm a little on edge.
- 炸弹舱检查完了吗？
- Bomb bay clear?
- 炸弹舱检查完毕
- Bomb bays clear.
- 右边检查完了吗？
- Clear on right?
- 检查完毕
- Clear on right.
- 左边检查完了吗？
- Clear on left?
- 检查完毕
- Clear on left.
他成功了，他成功了
He made it. He made it.
侧翼竖立
Get your flaps up.
嘿
Hey!
祝你们好运，小伙子们，剩下的都交给海军了
Good luck, fellows. Hand them a couple for the Navy.
- 我们会的，米勒
- We sure will, Miller.
- 也感谢你
- And thanks to you.
真希望我和你在一起。再见
Wish I were going with you. So long.
- 再见
- So long.
再见，小伙子们
Goodbye, boys.
- 我们前面还有四架
- Four more ahead of us.
- 启动引擎
- Let's start the engines.
走吧
Let's go.
- 右边检查完了吗？
- Clear on right?
检查完毕
Clear on right.
左边检查完了吗？
Clear on left?
检查完毕
Clear on left.
这些海军在催我们走
Those Navy guys are moving up to push us over.
他们不可能把我们扔出去
They're not gonna toss this ship overboard.
来呀宝贝，使把劲
Come on, baby. Give.
使把劲，使把劲
Give. Give.
检查油压
Check hydraulic pressure.
- 油压正常
- Hydraulic pressure okay.
- 检查刹车压力
- Check brake pressure.
正常
Okay.
鲍勃我们走了
There goes Bob.
我们前面还有两架
Two more ahead of us.
检查燃料加压器
Check fuel booster.
嘿，陆军，特德
Hey, Army. Ted!
给我也带些
Give them for me.
我们到重庆时，会告诉他们海军也干得不错
When we get to Chungking, we'll tell them it was a Navy show too.
他们会发现你们一文不值，加油干
They'll know that when they see how broke you are. Good hunting.
- 炸弹舱门关闭
- Bomb bay doors closed.
- 炸弹舱关闭
- Bomb bays closed.
- 飞行员呼叫炮手，准备就绪了，撒切尔
- Pilot to gunner. All set, Thatcher?
- 一切就绪，长官
- Everything okay, sir.
- 机翼下垂
- Wing flaps down.
- 机翼下垂了
- Wing flaps coming down.
霍尔马科走了
There goes Hallmark.
我们要走了，伙计们和你们一起真好
We're taking off, fellows. Happy landings.
嘿
Phew!
耶
Yeah.
双侧机翼竖立
Both the flaps up.
我们没有把它们放下
We didn't even have them down.
- 你觉得怎么样？
- How do you like that?
- 我想想还忘了什么
- I wonder what else we forgot.
咖啡、三明治、水，够了
Coffee, sandwiches, water, plenty.
飞行员呼叫炮手，撒切尔
Pilot to gunner. Thatcher.
炮手回复飞行员，请讲，长官
Gunner to pilot. Go ahead, sir.
- 你还好吧，撒切尔？
- You all right, Thatcher?
- 还好，长官
- Yes, sir.
你最好开始用一下那些罐子了
You'd better get started on those cans.
- 我们已经用掉了40加仑了
- We've burned over 40 gallons already.
- 好的，长官
- Yes, sir.
各位，我们开始上路了
Well, we're on our way.
如果有人走狗屎运了，一定不要放过
If anybody's carrying a rabbit's foot, hang on to it tight.
我们的位置，麦克卢尔
What's our position, McClure?
我估计离海岸还有1小时58分钟
I figure about an hour and 58 minutes from the coast.
听见了吗，撒切尔？我们现在可以随时遇到敌机
Get that, Thatcher? We can expect their fighters any time  now.
- 保持警惕
- Keep your eyes open.
- 时刻注意，长官
- Watching, sir.
什么都看不见需要试一试这个炮塔吗？
There's nothing in sight. Could we try out this turret again?
好，打开继电器开关
Okay. Relay switch on.
运转正常，先生
It works all right, sir,
但如果我们遇到麻烦备用动力不能维持多久
but that emergency power's not going to hold out long if we run into trouble.
那我们就关掉它
Turning it off now.
- 我们离第一批人有多远？
- Turning it off now.
- 大概一小时
- About an hour.
那我们真的应该想想怎么应对麻烦
Then we really can get set for trouble.
是的，但是不像后面那些人遇到的那样
Yeah, but nothing like what the guys behind us are going to run into.
晚上执行任务我会感觉要好一些
I'd feel a lot better on a night job.
你听见左侧发动机熄火了吗？
Did you hear that left engine miss?
没有，象是有人在嬉笑
No, singing like a lark.
我得听听声音
I must be hearing things.
领航员呼叫飞行员
Navigator to pilot.
飞行员回复领航员，请讲
Pilot to Navigator. Go ahead.
我们应该不久就到达日本海岸
We ought to hit the Japanese coast any minute.
快看
Look.
- 看见那个旗子了吗？
- See that flag?
- 看见了
- Yeah.
- 今天节省炸弹
- Saving bombs today.
- 他们在向我们挥舞示意
- They're waving at us.
他们肯定疯了
Those guys must be nuts.
直飞日本海岸
Japanese coast straight ahead.
富士山
Fujiyama.
我们现在可以丢点铅弹
We'll be catching buckshot any second now.
零式
Zeros.
- 飞行员呼叫…
- Pilot to...
- 我看见了，长官
- I saw them, sir.
- 要我打开炮塔的电源吗？
- Shall I turn the power on for the turret?
- 不，等一下
- No, wait a minute.
我不知道他们怎么了，长官，我想他们没有看见我们
I don't know what happened to them, sir. I guess they didn't see us.
既然都来了，就好好看一下
There she is fellows. Take a good gander.
当我们凯旋的时候
When we get back home, the folks will want to know what
人们肯定会问我们东京怎么样
Tokyo used to look like.
那肯定是戴维.琼斯的工作了
That must be Davey Jones giving them the works.
飞行员呼叫投弹手，投弹舱开启
Pilot to bombardier，bomb bay doors open.
- 我们到了，大红烟囱
- There we are, the big red smokestack.
- 飞行员呼叫投弹手
- Pilot to bombardier,
- 接近冶炼厂
- approaching smelter.
- 准备好了
- I'm on it.
他们也来了
They've got our altitude.
一个
One away.
两个
Two away.
三个
Three away.
四个
Four away.
- 三架战机出现在右上方
- Six fighters just above and to the right.
- 看见了吗，撒切尔？
- Have you got them, Thatcher?
准备好了，长官
Ready for them, sir.
他们为何不俯冲？
Why don't they dive?
他们离开了
They're going away.
我们不等他们回来了，我们自己离开这儿
We're not going to wait for them to come back. We're getting out of here.
好吧，我想我们挺幸运的
Well, I guess maybe we're in that lucky half.
说不定呢，我们还没到中国
Not yet. Not till we get to China.
真头痛
Wow. What a headache.
- 你害怕吗？
- Were you scared?
- 我一直很害怕
- I'm still scared.
- 麦克卢尔，一切按计划吗？
- McClure, on our course?
- 是的
- On our course.
160加仑，我希望这能坚持到常州
A hundred and sixty gallons. I hope it's enough to get us to Changchow.
而且也不要日本人先去了那里
Yeah, and I hope the Japs don't get there first.
消息怎么样，麦克卢尔？
What's the dope, McClure?
离常州200英里
About 200 miles to Changchow.
- 我们马上就要到达海岸了
- And we ought to hit the coast any minute.
- 黑暗里我们就找不到了
- We'll never find it in the dark
飞行员呼叫全体机组
Pilot to crew.
我们正在按仪表飞行，一旦燃料用完，我们就跳伞
We're going up and flying on instruments. When the gas is gone we'll bail out.
我们快用光了，也许可以着陆，注意一下暗礁和原木
We'll buzz it. Maybe we can land. Keep a lookout for rocks or logs.
着陆准备就绪，麦克卢尔，把枪带上
All set for landing. McClure, get our guns out.
脱掉降落伞，把救生衣带上带上枪
Take off chutes and be sure your life jackets are on. Carry your guns.
轮子放下，机翼放下
Wheels down. Flaps down.
空速135
Air speed 135.
空速110
我的飞机没了
I lost my ship.
- 你伤得重吗？
- You hurt bad?
- 我不…我不知道
- I don't... I don't know.
我的手不能动了
I can't move my arms.
你的腿，都快断了，长官
Your leg, it's all busted up, sir.
找到达文波特了
Get Davenport.
特德，特德，看着我
Ted, Ted, look at me.
孩子和我
That baby and I...
不需要任何东西，除了你…
We won't ever need anything but you.
我们谁都不准害怕，特德
We mustn't either of us be scared about it, Ted,
因为我们的孩子是我坚信你会回来的理由
because the baby, the baby's why I know you're coming back to us.
劳森
Lawson!
我能开枪吗，上尉？
Shall I shoot them, Lieutenant?
不，别开枪
No, hold it.
- 但他们可能是日本人，长官
- But they may be Japs, sir.
- 别开枪，撒切尔
- Don't shoot, Thatcher.
喂
Hey! Hey!
他说他是中国人，他说的是“美国人”？
He says he's Chinese. What's that word for American?
这只脚需要缝合，长官
That leg's got to be sewn up, sir.
它已经爆裂了
It's split wide open.
我，查理
Me, Charlie.
美国人
Americans.
- 我们是美国人
- We're Americans.
- 美国人
- American.
美国人
Americans.
我们需要医生，我们需要帮助
We need a doctor, and some help
到常州
to get to Changchow.
陈开圣
Chiang Kai-shek.
- 我们是朋友，在重庆
- We're his friends. In Chungking.
- 重庆
- Chungking!
- 是的
- Yes.
- 太好了
- That's right.
我们去重庆
We go Chungking.
重庆很多很多天
Chungking many, many days. Many.
医生，医生
Doctor. Doctor.
查理，去叫医生，医生，查理，请一个医生来
Charlie, go, go doctor. Charlie, bring doctor here.
查理，请一个医生来不然我们会死的
Charlie, bring doctor or we die.
医生，有一里远
Doctor, one li.
里是中国的距离单位
One li, that's a Chinese mile.
一里，去
One li. Go.
请医生来
Bring doctor.
医生，日本人，日本医生
Doctor, Japanese man. Japanese doctor.
也许是日本人，日本兵
Maybe Japanese man, Japanese soldier,
过来
come here.
日本人晚上不来
Japanese man no come at night.
船，你们坐船去
Boat, you go boat.
走吧
Let's go.
嘿，干什么？
Hey, cut that out.
我想他想和你交换子弹，撒切尔
I think he wants to trade bullets with you, Thatcher.
朋友
Friend.
查理，朋友
Charlie, friend.
查理，走，查理，朋友
Charlie, go. Charlie, friend.
当然，查理，朋友，再见，查理
Sure, Charlie, friend. Goodbye, Charlie.
日本人肯定就在我们周围
The Japs must be all around us.
- 我想知道其他人去哪里了？
- I wonder where the rest of the gang is?
- 散落在中国的海岸线上了
- Scattered all over the China coast,
如果他们还活着的话
if they're alive.
我以为我快死了
I think I'm going to pass out.
我，特德娶艾伦，为我的合法妻子
I, Ted, take you, Ellen. To be my lawfully wedded wife.
为我的合法妻子
To be my lawfully wedded wife.
- 拥有并且珍惜
- To have and to cherish.
- 拥有并且珍惜…
直至死亡分离
Until death us do part.
不要切断我的腿，求你了，不要切断我的腿
Don't let them cut my leg off. Please, don't let them cut my leg off.
- 不要让他们切断我的腿
- Don't let them cut my leg off.
- 劳森，停下来，劳森，
- Lawson, stop it. Lawson.
- 不要
- Don't.
- 劳森
- Lawson.
- 怎么了？
- What's the matter?
- 你在大叫
- You were yelling.
谢谢
Thank you.
我叫傅苓
My name is Foo Ling.
我们的东西你们都可以用
Everything we have is yours.
我们知道你们做的一切，我们很敬重你们
We know what you have done and we honor you for it.
我们的领航员两只胳膊断了
Our navigator has both his shoulders broken.
有人可以给他安好吗？
Is there anybody who can set them for him?
没有人
No one.
但我们希望帮助能尽快抵达
But we hope that help will soon arrive for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
他们怎么样？
How are they?
我们给他们清洗了一下，正在绑伤口
We have washed them. They are bandaged.
但是我们没有药
But we have no medicines.
连阿司匹林都没有
Not even aspirin.
怎么了？
What's that?
- 这是陈医生
- This is Dr. Chung.
- 你好
- How do you do?
我们走了很久，正准备返程
We've come a long way and we're going home now
我们一直在到处寻找医生
and we've been hunting a doctor everywhere.
我明白
I understand.
你有什么其它办法能解救他们吗？他们都要痛死了
Have you got anything that'll knock them out, Doctor? They're in awful pain.
我去一趟我爸爸的医院，也许就能得到一些药品了
We hope to have some medical supplies by the time we reach my father's hospital.
医院，在哪里？
Hospital? Where's that?
在临海，离这里有60里远
In Lin Hai. About 60 li from here.
- 我来把你们接过去
- I have come to take you there.
- 这太好笑了
- It's a funny thing, Doctor.
还有很多的飞机，我们得尽早启程
There were a lot of planes and we had to take off early.
- 你看见了吧？
- You see how it was.
- 当然
- Of course.
他们这状况是不能走远路的，医生
They aren't in any shape to make much of a trip, Doctor.
但我们得马上转移他们
We'll have to move them at once.
日本人昨天抓住了你们的一个人，离这儿不远
The Japanese captured one of your crews yesterday, not very far from here.
很多飞机，我们不知道其他人情况怎么样了
So many planes, and we don't know what happened to the others.
全都在中国海岸带上了
All up and down the Chinese Coast.
我的同胞正在寻找你们的人
My countrymen are seeking your countrymen.
我们会把他们带来的
We'll bring them through.
我有一些钱，我想把它给你
I have some money. I want to give it to you.
请别，中尉，你已经给了我们很多了
Please, Lieutenant, you have given us enough already.
- 为什么？
- What?
- The bombs you dropped on Japan.
- 你们在日本投下了炸弹
现在请试着休息吧
Please, now try to rest.
日本人现在在我们刚才离开的那个村子
The Japanese, they are in the village we just left.
- 陈
- Chan.
- 派克先生
- Mr. Parker.
- 派克太太
- Mrs. Parker.
- 陈医生
- Doctor Chan.
- 他们怎样？
- How are they?
- 他们状况很不好
- They are very, very sick.
- 我需要你的帮助
- I'll need your help.
- 日本人有多近
- How close are the Japanese?
我们离开三个小时后他们占领了三明
They took Ching Ming three hours after our departure.
有一个美国人已经落入了他们手中
One of the American crews has already fallen into their hands.
为什么不把他们直接送到更好的何塞医院？
Hadn't they better be taken straight through to Hop Sai?
他们受不了长途颠簸
They couldn't stand the trip.
这是我爸爸，陈医生
This is my father, Dr. Chung.
- 其他人，求求你，救救他们
- The others, please, help them.
- 不要担心，中尉
- Please, don't worry, Lieutenant.
我们会照顾好每个人的
We'll take care of everybody.
你不会把它锯掉吧，医生？
You won't have to take it off, will you, Doc?
我们不希望，但谁也说不准
We hope not. One cannot tell.
你们已经走了很久了，现在你必须休息
You've had a long journey. Now you must rest.
我们有的就是一点消毒水和一些绷带
All we had at our Mission was a little antiseptic fluid and some bandages.
但我们已经叫信使去请求药物了
But we've sent out runners for supplies.
有什么办法可以让我把消息送出去吗？
Is there any way I could get a message out?
我想让我母亲知道我还好
I'd like my mother to know that I'm okay.
整个地区都被日本人占领了
The whole region's swarming with Japanese.
你们觉得合众国知道发生在我们身上的事吗？
Well, do you think they've heard back in the States what happened to us?
我们一直在听短波他们都知道了空袭
We've been listening in on short wave. They know all about the raid,
但显然，细节并没有被披露
but apparently they're keeping the details secret
要等到你们剩下的人得救以后
until the rest of your men have been saved.
你们找到其他人了吗？
Have they found any of the others?
我得到消息说，有一队人成功脱险也快到这里了
We have word that one crew will be coming through here pretty soon now.
我明白，他们中间有一个医生
I understand there's a doctor among them.
肯定是史密斯中尉那一帮人，抱歉
Oh, that must be Lieutenant Smith's crew. Excuse me.
史密斯中尉那一帮人被解救了，长官
Lieutenant Smith's crew has been rescued, sir.
史密斯他们？
Smith's?
他们发现了史密斯中尉和怀特医生他们正赶过来
They found Lieutenant Smith and Doc White and they're coming here.
唐.史密斯的人那个医生和唐.史密斯一起飞行
Don Smith's crew. The Doc was flying with Don Smith.
他们现在很快就要到了
They'll be here any minute now.
真有意思，是吧？
It's funny, isn't it?
我的意思是克勒文走的路线也很颠簸啊
I mean the way Clever's head just keeps rocking back and forth,
很颠簸
back and forth.
一定是有人救了克勒文
Somebody ought to help Clever.
我觉得中国人真好
I think the Chinese are a swell bunch of people
但我不敢说他们的音乐
but I can't say I go for their music.
肖特.门奇听到一小段这个肯定会崩溃的
Shorty Manch would go all to pieces if he heard a little of this.
对
Yeah.
劳森怎样了？
How's Lawson?
他的腿看着很糟糕，长官
Well, his leg looks pretty bad, sir.
陈医生觉得里面已经坏死了
Dr. Chung thinks gangrene has set in.
好像是日本零式飞机
Looks like a Jap Zero.
你们应该不管我，继续走下去
You guys ought to go on and leave me.
我经常觉得我就要死掉了我听见他们说什么了
They think I'm passed out half the time and I hear what they say.
日本人正在不断逼近，你们为什么不走？
The Japs are coming closer all the time. Why don't you guys go?
我们不在这儿逗留是因为你，劳森
We're not sticking around here because of you, Lawson.
- 我们都不能长途旅行
- None of us here are able to travel yet.
- 我在想
- I was just thinking.
我想我和艾伦再也不能滑雪了
I guess Ellen and I aren't going to ski anymore.
那太糟了
That's too bad.
我会给她讲一些有意思的东西
I was going to teach her some fancy stuff.
别那样说，你正在恢复健康
Now don't start talking like that. You're going to pull through all right.
你觉得一个女孩会怎样？我是说艾伦和我都很喜欢滑雪
What do you think a girl would do? I mean, say Ellen and I like to ski.
他们把我的脚锯掉，真有点搞笑，不是吗？
Be kind of funny if they cut my leg off, wouldn't it?
你为什么不试看睡会儿觉
Why don't you try to go to sleep?
是有点搞笑
Yeah, it'd be kind of funny, all right.
你和一个有两只胳膊两条腿的人结了婚
You marry a guy, he's got two arms and two legs.
然后他回来了，但什么都没有了
Then he comes back and he hasn't any.
- 我是张医生
- I am Dr. Chung.
- 那些小伙子呢？
- Where are the boys?
你好，老爹
How are you, Pop?
路上还好吧？
Did you have a good trip?
- 在这儿呢
- Here they are.
- 嘿，伙计们
- Hi, fellas.
- 怎么样了？
- How are you?
- 你还好吧？
- How you doing?
- 你好，军士
- Hello, Sarge.
- 见到你们真高兴
- It's good to see you.
- 天啊，你们到底发生了什么？
- Holy Joe, what happened to you guys?
- 不是很严重
- Nothing serious.
“鸭子”忘记凫水了
The Duck forgot to duck.
是啊，麦克卢尔在尽力做好他的飞行
Yeah, McClure's been trying to do his own flying ever since.
真像大屠杀的幸存者
This really looks like something left over from a massacre.
你们看起来也不好啊
Well, you guys don't look so good yourselves.
闻起来也是
You don't smell so good either.
这不是我们的错，好好洗一次澡也无济于事
Well, there's nothing wrong with us that a good bath won't fix.
- 我也想这么说
- I wish we could say the same for you.
- 这儿的伙食怎么样？
- How's the grub around here?
我想吃上等的厚牛排和法国炸洋葱
I think I'd like a good thick steak, French fried onions
还有烤土豆，多加点黄油
and a baked potato with plenty of butter
再来三瓶酒…
and about three bottles of beer...
你只有吃豆芽之类的东西
You'll take bean sprouts and like them.
- 劳森和达文波特在哪儿？
- Say, where's Lawson and Davenport?
- 他们在楼上
- They're upstairs.
- 劳森的状况很不好
- Lawson's in pretty bad shape.
- 你最好去看看他
- You better go up and see him.
他很需要你，医生
He needs you bad, Doc.
再次见到你们，真的感觉很好
Well, it's certainly good to see you fellows again.
嘿，老爹，这里的炒杂烩菜怎么样
Hey, Pop, how's the chop suey around here?
他不会说英语
He doesn't speak English.
对不起，老爹
I'm sorry, Pop.
肖特跳下来时，他带上了有两把点45，一把点44来复枪
Yeah, and when Shorty jumped, he had two. 45s, a. 44 rifle,
一把点22自动枪，他自己的鲁格尔手枪，一把猎刀，一把猎刀
a. 22 automatic, that Luger of his, a hunting knife, a Bowie knife
- 和一柄斧子
- and an ax.
- 真走运
- What a guy.
他把自己的衬衣里塞满了巧克力棒，但却忘了系上衣领扣
He stuffed his shirt full of chocolate bars but he forgot to button his collar.
所以当他拉开开降绳时
So when he pulled the rip cord,
他的那些糖果就掉在中国北方的土地上了
he just naturally molted candy all over North China.
- 他的照片呢？
- What happened to his photograph?
- 和飞机一起没了
- It went down with the ship.
第二天早上门奇被中国人的少见多怪吓住了
Next morning Manch scared the Chinese right out of their wits.
他们不知道人类可以长这么高
They didn't know anything human grew that tall.
鲍勃.格雷呢？
What about Bob Gray?
他很好，我在想他已经动身去重庆了
He's okay. I think they moved on to Chungking.
哦，好吧，那个家伙“我，查理”代我问你们好
Oh, yeah, and that guy "Me, Charlie" said to tell you hello.
如果不是查理的话我们第一天就被日本人抓住了
If it hadn't been for Charlie, the Japs would have had us that first day.
是啊，我们也是
Yeah, us too.
总有一天我要回去和那个人并肩作战
I'd like to come back some day and fight alongside that guy.
我们也是
Me, too.
好了，今天就到这儿了
Well, it's all over.
让我们节省点话题留到明天
Let's save some of this talk for tomorrow.
一品脱半，还不错
A pint and a half, that's not bad.
你们该睡觉了
You'd better get to bed now.
你真是个老奶奶，医生
You're an old grandma, Doc.
但是我会慢点的，作为对你的感激
But I'll take it slow, just as a favor to you.
再会，劳森
Be seeing you, Lawson.
谢谢医生
Thanks, Doc.
腿怎么样，医生？
How's the leg, Doc?
不算好，劳森
It's not good, Lawson.
接下来的48小时要下个决断
The next forty-eight hours will tell the story.
好吧，谢谢你
Well, thank you.
- 嘿，唐
- Hey, Don.
- 哦
- Yeah?
告诉杜利德，我们到了以后搞一个派对
Tell Doolittle to hold off that party till we get there.
好的，达文波特，我们等你
Okay, Davenport. We'll wait for you.
- 撒切尔呢？
- Where's Thatcher?
- 他和劳森在一起，他很好
- He's in with Lawson. He'll be right out.
我希望你在康复之前, 让我一直待在这里
I wish you would let me stay here until you're ready to go, sir.
这些人会很好的照顾我的
These people will take care of us.
你们没有理由留在附近, 而且还有可能被抓到
There's no reason for you fellows to hang around and maybe get caught.
是啊，我知道，但如果日本人来了，我们迟早都要走
Yeah, I know, but I might come in handy if the Japs show up, sir.
撒切尔，当你回到美国的时候
Thatcher, when you get back to the States,
如果遇见了我的妻子
if you should run into my wife,
就告诉她我很好
just tell her I'm okay.
不要让她知道有什么不对劲了
Don't let her know about anything being wrong.
我明白，长官
I understand, sir.
代我向那个比令斯的女孩问个好
And say hello for me to that girl in Billings.
我会的，长官
That I will, sir.
- 再见
- Goodbye.
- 再见，撒切尔
- Goodbye, Thatcher.
早上好
Good morning.
- 早上好，劳森
- Good morning, Lawson.
- 你好，医生
- Hi, Doc.
我尽量不伤着你，劳森，我得仔细看看伤口
I'll try not to hurt you, Lawson. I'll have a look at this.
谢谢
Thanks.
你要割下这条腿吗？
You going to take the leg, Doc?
我想是这样的
Yeah, I think so.
我们讨论过了，除此之外别无他法
We talked it over and there's nothing else to do.
把一个人的腿割下有些不近人情
It's pretty rough to have to cut a man's leg off.
但我觉得没什么事
I guess it'll be all right.
毕竟，一只木脚就像一个高脚背的脚穿上了一只鞋
After all, a wooden leg is just kind of like wearing a shoe with a high instep.
什么时候开始？
When are you gonna do it?
现在我会给你打一针
I might as well give you a shot right now.
你是说你有什么东西可以让我昏过去？
You mean we have something to knock me out?
我们的信使今早带来了麻醉剂
Our runners arrived with anesthetic this morning.
只是脊柱麻醉，劳森
It'll only be a spinal, Lawson.
腰部以下你不会有任何疼痛感, 但还是会有知觉
You won't feel anything from the waist down, but you'll be conscious.
这已经是最好的了
That's the best we can do.
好的
Oh, swell.
我会仔细看着你们不会让你们多割下一点
I can watch you and make sure you don't take off too much.
好的，劳森,我们要把你反转过来了
All right, Lawson. We'll have to roll you over.
可能会花上一些时间
It'll take a little time to work.
我们把你反过来到手术室里去
We'll get you over to the operating room.
- 医生
- Doc?
- 是的
- Yes?
- 你们会切多高？
- How high are you going to cut?
- 不会太高
- Oh, not too high.
- 我会有膝盖吗，医生？
- Will I have a knee, Doc?
- 恐怕没有了，劳森
- I'm afraid not, Lawson.
- 有感觉吗？
- Any feeling there?
- 没有，医生，我…
- No. Look, Doc.
当麻醉剂作用消失前, 我们不能浪费时间
We can't waste any time, Lawson. When that anesthetic wears off,
- 我们没时间了
- we haven't got any more.
- 好的，只有一件事
- Okay, but just one thing more.
说吧
Yes.
如果发生什么不测
If anything happens,
不要让艾伦知道有这手术的事
don't let Ellen know anything about the operation.
她最好能够以为我是完整的死去的
She might just as well think I died while all in one piece.
好的，劳森。现在你没有感觉了
All right, Lawson. Now, you're not going to feel this.
但你有可能紧张跳起来或是怎么的
But you might get nervous and jump or something,
所以护士们要抓紧你
so the nurses are going to hold you.
好的，医生
Okay, Doc.
开工吧
Fire away.
当你说：“没有膝盖”时你没开玩笑吧？
Oh, when you said "no knee," you weren't kidding.
如果我切低了，一切都得重来
If I cut any lower we might have to do it again
你的身体肯定受不了
and your system couldn't take it.
麻醉效力怎么了，医生？
What're you stalling for, Doc?
我们在尽力，劳森，放松一点
We're doing the best we can, Lawson. Take it easy.
好的，只是再快一点
Okay. Only hurry.
好像我能感觉到另一只脚了
It seems like I'm beginning to feel my other leg.
好像我的脚能动了，医生
It seems like I can move my toes, Doc.
我想我能转动我的脚踝了，快点，医生，我想我能转动了
I think I can move my ankle. Hurry, Doc, I'm sure I can.
快点，医生，快点
Hurry, Doc, hurry.
- 喂
- Hello.
- 喂，艾伦
- Hello. Hello, Ellen?
- 特德，你在哪儿？
- Ted, where are you?
- 我在一个木屋里
- I'm in a lumber camp.
我必须在一个泥坑里强行着陆
I had to make a forced landing in a mud puddle.
- 你没受伤吧？
- You aren't hurt, are you?
- 不，一点儿伤都没有
- No, not a scratch.
- 你把圣诞树都装饰好了吗？
- Have you got the tree all fixed?
- 是的，特德，你真该来看看
- Oh, yes, Ted. You should just see it.
太美了
It's so beautiful.
树下有东西吗
Anything under it?
- 哦是的
- Oh, yes.
- 好的，让我们打开看看
- Well, let's open them up.
- 我们不能那样
- Oh, we can't do that.
- 我们可以，去打开
- Sure we can. Go ahead.
那好吧，你这样说了
Well, if you say so
我的飞机毁了，这个圣诞节有被骗的感党
I'm not going to be cheated out of my Christmas by a cracked up airplane.
哦，特德，这是我一生中见过的…
Oh, Ted, it's the most beautiful
最美的一盒糖果
box of candy I've ever seen in my whole life.
周围还有什么吗？
Good. Isn't there maybe something else lying around?
- 让我瞧瞧，还有
- Let me see. Yes, there is.
- 好的，打开看看
- Well, open it.
是一个丝巾，好像是手工制的
It's a silk scarf. And it looks like it's handmade, too.
- 上面有我名字的首字母
- I'll bet it's got my initials on it.
- 这不公平
- That's not fair.
我打开时你偷偷看了一眼
You peeked while I was making it.
我是了解我的妻子啊
I just know my wife.
- 特德，我真想你在我的身边
- Oh, Ted, I wish you were here.
- 我也是，甜心
- So do I, honey.
今晚我会想你的
I'll be thinking of you tonight.
我会坐在圣诞树下，打开收音机，放着圣诞颂歌
I'll sit in front of the tree and turn the radio on to Christmas carols
不停想念你
and just think of you.
谢谢你们，谢谢你们，童子军
Thank you. And thank you, scouts.
我们所有人都由衷感谢你们…
I mean, all the fellows would like to thank you very much,
为我们付出的所有
for everything.
中尉，我父亲叫我把这个给你们
Lieutenant, my father has asked me to present this to you.
它从15世纪开始就一直留在我们家了
It has been in our family since the fifteenth century.
父亲让我告诉你美好的东西永远属于美丽的人
Father begs me to tell you that beauty belongs to beauty,
让你把这个东西带给你的妻子就算是对她的敬意了
and asks that you honor him by presenting it to your wife.
哦，谢谢，谢谢
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
我没想到你知道艾伦，我的妻子
I didn't know that you knew about Ellen, my wife.
你说过很多次了
You spoke of her a number of times.
上面写着：“这是在日本投下炸弹的美国英雄
It says, "This is an American hero who has bombed Japan.
当他们来到中国人中间时
"Whenever he goes among the people of China,
让他得到尊重和荣誉
"let him be accorded respect and honor. "
他刚从高材村来
He has just come from Kow Chai.
你们有一个人被捕了
Another one of your crews has been captured
日本人正朝这个方向来
and the Japanese are moving in this direction.
我想过几天，劳森才能行走
I think Lawson will be able to travel in a couple of days.
没有什么，医生，我现在就可以走了
There's nothing wrong with me, Doc. I can travel right now.
我担心几天的时间太长了
I'm afraid a couple of days will be too long.
这是王强
This is Wang Tsung.
他从他们的高材村一路赶来
He has walked all the way from his native village of Kow Chai.
他想送给美军盟友们一件表达敬意的礼物
And he begs the honor of presenting gifts to his American Allies.
谢谢
Thank you.
Thanks.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢，非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you very much.
他感觉比我还糟
He felt a lot worse than I did.
我已经感觉好多了
There, I can get along pretty well already.
我必须得说，你第一次下床，康复得非常好
I should say very well for your first day out of bed.
我觉得我还要小心一点
I guess, I'll have to be a little more careful.
我可不想让人看见我这样
I don't ever want anybody to see me do that.
我想让人看看，我有了一只新脚了
I don't want anybody to see me till I get a new leg.
怀特中尉的消息
Lieutenant White, word just came.
美军飞机将在明天下午5点从衢州机场接你们离开
The American plane will pick you up in Changchow tomorrow afternoon at 5:00.
太好了
Wonderful.
他说如果我们不快点的话日本人就要捷足先登了
He says if we don't hurry, the Japanese may get there first.
- 你们什么时候走？
- When are you leaving?
- 我们想待在这里
- We're going to stay here.
我们已经很习惯了
We're quite used to it, you know.
- 来，这些能派上用场
- Here. This may come in handy.
- 谢谢
- Thank you.
你和派克先生为我们做了很多
You and Mr. Parker have done so much for us,
我们不会忘记的
and we'll never forget it.
- 再见，劳森
- Goodbye, Lawson.
- 再见
- Goodbye.
- 祝你好运
- Good luck.
- 谢谢！先生
- Thank you, sir.
- 再见，愿上帝保佑你
- Goodbye. God bless you.
- 再见，谢谢
- Goodbye. Thank you.
我父亲想让我告诉你们你们的到来让他觉得很光荣
My father wishes me to tell you that you have honored us with your visit
他会一直为你们的平安回国祈祷的
and that he will offer prayers for your safe return to America.
他不和我们一起走吗？
Isn't he coming along with us?
父亲要和他的老乡们待在一起
Father feels that he must stay with his people.
这里的人们需要他
They will need him here.
再见，先生
Goodbye, sir.
- 再见，医生
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- 再见，先生
- Goodbye, sir.
再见，医生，感谢你们做的一切
Goodbye, Doc, and thanks for everything.
但愿我们能再次相见
I hope, sir, that we may meet again. That goes double, Doc.
再见，医生，谢谢你
Goodbye, Doctor, and thank you.
谢谢你
Thank you.
如果有机会到美国来，来找我好吗？
If you ever come to the States, Doctor, look me up, will you?
在波特兰的黄页里找得到我
I'll be in the Portland telephone directory.
- 荣幸之至
- With pleasure.
- 再见，医生
- Goodbye, Doctor.
我很难过，中尉
I have one sorrow, Lieutenant,
我们没有足够的药品来减轻你的疼痛
that we did not have the medicine to ease your pain.
- 你救了我的命，医生
- You saved my life, Doc.
- 我希望有一天你还能回来
- I hope someday you will come back to us.
我会回来的，也许不是我们自己
We'll be back, maybe not us ourselves
有可能是像我们这样的其他人我很愿意成为他们当中的一员
but a lot of guys like us. And I'd like to be with them.
- 因为你们是我们最亲近的人
- Because you're our kind of people.
- 谢谢，先生，再见
- Thank you, sir, and goodbye.
- 你好
- Hello.
- 来坐下
- Go ahead, sit down.
- 谢谢
- Thank you.
我知道你的感觉，握着试一试
I know how you feel. Take it for a while.
谢谢
Thanks.
感觉到了吗？
Smell that?
那是美利坚，那是美国
That's America. That's the USA.
每一次我航行归来时她都变得更加光彩照人
Every time I make a trip back, she smells better and better.
是啊
Yeah.
- 我想我知道你的意思
- I think I know what you mean.
- 我来自匹兹堡
- I'm from Pittsburgh.
可能你觉得很怪，但是…
I know it may seem screwy to you, but
我能隐隐约约闻到煤烟的味道
it seems to me as if I can smell some of that coal smoke
马上就到老孟农加希拉河了，有点不可思议吧？
right off the old Monongahela River. That sound crazy?
不，我来自加州，已经闻道橘子的味道了
No. I'm from California and I can smell orange blossoms.
不可能，那儿太远了，绝对是来自佛罗里达的
Oh, it couldn't be, that's too far. It must come from Florida.
如果你想吃的话，一定得吃加州的橘子
Oh, if you want flavor, you've got to have a California orange,
但只是闻闻的话，佛罗里达就够了
but for smelling, Florida's just as good.
喂…是的
Hello. Yes.
什么？
What's that?
- 等一会儿，艾伦
- Just a minute. Ellen.
- 什么？
- Yes?
艾伦，华盛顿来的电话
Ellen, Washington on the phone.
你好？
Hello?
你好，我是劳森夫人
Yes, this is Mrs. Lawson.
你好，上校，我是说杜利德将军
Hello, Colonel. I mean General Doolittle.
哦，我很好，谢谢
Oh, yes, I'm fine, thank you.
不，非常兴奋，将军
No, not a bit excited, General.
他回来了，妈妈，特德回来了，他回来了
Oh, he's back, Mother. Ted's back. He's back.
好的将军，他怎么样了
Oh yes, General, how is he?
哦，这个
Oh, yes.
我能理解
I understand.
我然，我接受的了
Of course, I do.
是的，我有准备了
Yes, I'll be ready.
我知道，我知道
I know, I know.
你真的很好，将军
Oh, that's so nice of you, General.
好的，谢谢哦！谢谢你，将军
Yes, thank you. Oh, yes, thank you, General.
谢谢
Thank you.
哭出来吧，亲爱的
Just cry, darling.
哭出来
Cry it out.
他今天早上到的，妈妈
He got in this morning, Mother.
杜利德将军刚才见到了他了，这是真的
General Doolittle just saw him, so it's true.
杜利德将军给我寄了一张机票
General Doolittle's sending a plane ticket for me.
特德不想见我
Ted doesn't want to see me.
他不想见我，因为他失去了一条腿
He doesn't want to see me because he's lost his leg
他甚至想把我瞒住
and he doesn't even want me to know it's happened
他有了一只新腿并且能用以后
till he gets a new leg and learns how to use it.
这都不重要
As if it would make any difference.
只要他还活着
As if anything would make any difference to me as long as he's alive.
哦，我得去见他，我得去见他
Oh, I'm going to see him, I'm going to see him.
好吧
Well
这意味这我们得赶紧打点行李
that means we have to get your clothes ready in a hurry.
我的衣服从洗衣房里取回来了吗？
Have my things come back from the cleaners yet?
我看我得带上这件衣服
Let's see, I'll take this suit.
和我的蓝外套，他最喜欢了
And my blue coat. He always liked it best.
我带不了这么多，我带不了这么多好看的衣服
I can't take any of these things. I can't take any of my pretty clothes.
我穿起来不合适了
They don't fit me anymore.
你觉得特德会注意吗？
Do you think Ted's going to pay any attention
会注意到你穿的衣服和你的样子吗？
to what kind of clothes you wear or how you look?
他会的
He always did.
妈妈，我很害怕
Oh, Mother, I'm scared.
没什么可怕的
There's nothing to be frightened about.
很多人都失去了脚或手
Lots of people lose a leg or arm
- 但还是继续过着正常人的生活
- and continue living perfectly normal lives.
- 我不是害怕特德
- I'm not scared about Ted.
- 我害怕我自己
- I'm scared about me.
- 你自己？
- About you?
你知道，时过境迁很多丈夫和妻子就分开了
Well, you see, most husbands and wives are together while things are changing.
丈夫总是那样因为…因为这总是在发生
Husbands get used to things like that because, well, they're around.
特德走了好长一段时间，这段时间我又瘦了
Ted's been gone all this time and when he went away, I was so slim.
每次他走了，他总会这样觉得
All the time he's been gone, he's been thinking of me like that.
特德爱你，爱伦，你也爱他
Ted loves you Ellen, and you love him.
这就是你们没有人会觉察到对方变化的原因
That's why neither of you is going to notice any change when you meet.
- 你这样认为吗，妈妈？
- Do you think so, Mother?
- 我是这样认为的
- I know so.
还有，如果我穿这样的衣服的话
All the same, if I held my coat like this
我走在屋子里，你不觉得有一点点…
when I walk into the room, don't you think it would hide me, just a little?
把我内心隐藏起来的感觉
你好，劳森，感觉如何？
Hello, Lawson. How're you feeling?
- 很好，长官
- Pretty good, sir.
- 你看起来不错
- You look fine.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
- 你不坐下吗，长官？
- Won't you sit down, sir?
- 哦，谢谢
- Yeah, thanks.
- 有什么打算？
- Well, got any plans?
- 关于什么？
- About what, sir?
是的，关于未来，你想做点什么？
Well, about the future. Have you decided what you're going to do?
没怎么想，长官
Not particularly, sir.
我一直想成为一个航空学工程师
I always wanted to be an aeronautical engineer.
退伍以后我想我得
重新学习
after they muster me out.
谁说你会退伍？
Who said they'd muster you out?
我对任何人都没什么用了，没有了…
Well, I won't be much use to anybody with a...
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
你认为我们会让拥有你这样经历的人离开吗？
Do you think we'd let a man of your experience get away from us?
- 很好，长官，谢谢
- Well, that's fine, sir. Thank you.
- 你不要谢我
- Don't thank me.
- 我突然想到了一些事，劳森
- I just happened to think of something, Lawson.
- 什么事？长官
- Yes, sir?
你的妻子呢？她知道你回来吗？
What about your wife? Does she knew you're back?
- 不，长官
- No, sir.
- 为什么不通知？
- Why not?
我想等我有一只新脚然后伤疤修复以后
Well, I thought I'd wait till I get my new leg and my scars fixed up.
那样她就不会感到很震惊了
It won't be so much of a shock to her that way.
震惊？你娶的是一个怎样的女孩？
Shock? What kind of a girl did you marry, anyway?
她很好，长官，她是一个出色的女孩
She's okay, sir. She's a fine girl.
那么她就应该知道…
Well then, she deserves to know.
并且应该看见你
She deserves to see you too.
不不，长官。如果你不介意，我会一直等下去
No, no, sir. If you don't mind, I'd rather wait.
当我再次见到艾伦时我一定会盛装打扮
When I see Ellen again, I'm going to be all dressed up
而且有了一只新腿
and have a new leg.
带她去镇上最好的地方
And I'm going to take her out to the best place in town
我要和她跳舞
and I'm going to dance with her.
- 那还要等上一段时间，劳森
- That may be quite a while, Lawson.
- 不，长官
- No, sir.
你瞧我康复得很快，可能一两个月…
You see, I'm getting along fine. And in a month or two...
两个月你就得工作了，繁重的工作
In a month or two you'll be back at work, hard work.
好吧，我会时常来看你的，劳森
Well, I'll try to drop in on you again, Lawson.
- 希望你能来，长官
- I hope you can, sir.
- 再见
- Goodbye.
再见，长官
Goodbye, sir
你妻子快生小孩了，是吧？
Your wife's going to have a baby, isn't she?
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
我也有孩子，两个，都在服役
I've got a couple of kids myself, both in the service.
劳森，如果我的孩子或者其他人的孩子遇到这种情况
You know, Lawson, if my kids and all the other kids who are in this thing
都能处理自如，当然我不想看到
could fix it so this would really be the last one,
你孩子会好起来的，是吧？
your kid would get quite a break, wouldn't he?
他会的，长官
He sure would, sir.
我不得不来
I just had to come.
特德，特德，特德，让我来帮你
Ted, Ted, Ted. Let me help you.
别这样，艾伦，会伤到孩子的
Don't, Ellen. You'll hurt the baby.
当最惨烈的时候
When things were worst,
当希望渺茫的时候
when there didn't seem to be any chance at all,
我能看见你的面庞，你隽秀的面庞
I could see your face, your beautiful face.
我知道你回来了，特德
I knew you were coming home, Ted.
告诉我，亲爱的
Tell me, honey.
为什么你这么可爱？
How come you're so cute?
我找到了一个如此帅气的小伙子，我必须得这样啊
I had to be if I was going to get such a good looking fellow.